<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<java version="1.7.0_01" class="java.beans.XMLDecoder">
 <object class="biowizard.dict.ArticlesList">
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Primary breast lymphomas are uncommon. All reported primary breast lymphomas were in the breast parenchyma. Here we reported the first case of primary nipple lymphoma in a 76-year-old woman initially diagnosed using a modified fine-needle aspiration method. The aspirated material by this method had yielded adequate material for both cytomorphologic and flowcytometric analysis, as well as for molecular analysis of light chain rearrangement. In smears the atypical lymphocytes were predominantly middle-sized with irregular nuclei. Scattered large centroblast or immunoblast-like cells, a few reactive lymphocytes,histocytes, and few plasma cells were also observed. These findings suggested a low-grade lymphoma that was further confirmed by flow cytometry (CD19+/CD3-, positive for cytoplasmic kappa light chain but negative for lambda light chain) and molecular analysis (monoclonal rearrangement of immunoglobulin kappa chain). Immunohistochemical stains performed on the excised specimen showed that the tumor cells were positive forCD20 and CD79a but negative for cytokeratin, CD3, CD5,CD10, CD23, CD43, CD45RO, bcl-6, and cyclin-D1. The Ki-67 proliferation index was less than 20%. Taking these together, the case was diagnosed as a primary MALT lymphoma of the nipple.FNA usually provides a better cell morphology than tissue sections, but pathologists have to face the sampling error and lack of immunophenotype information when subtyping lymphoma issues using FNA. With the help of flow cytometry and molecular analysis, more and more trials have proved the accuracy of FNA in diagnosis of lymphomas. Therefore, FNA could play an informative and diagnostic role in diagnosis of lymphoma</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22988573</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>A primary nipple lymphoma diagnosed by a modified fine-needle aspiration method.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Objectives. Clinical estimation of malignant breast tumor size is critical for preoperative planning and is crucial for following up the tumor's response to the therapy in case she receives a neoadjuvant chemotharapy. Ductal carcinoma in situ (DCIS) accompanies about 25.4% of detected invasive breast cancers. The aim of this study was to examine the effect of the presence of DCIS on the accuracy of the ultrasonographic measuring malignant breast tumor size using B-mode and real time elastography. Materials and Methods. We recruited histologically confirmed breast cancer patients in a prospective observational study. Results. We recruited 50 breast cancer patients with a median age of 57.5 years. DCIS was confirmed to accompany 42% (n = 21) of the cases. Tumor size estimation using B-mode sonography (P < 0.001) as well as using real time elastography (P < 0.001). was statistically significant correlated to the actual tumor size. Presence of DCIS in 42% of our recruited patients affected the tumor size estimation using both methods thus losing the correlation between both estimations (P = 0.794). Conclusion. This study shows that the presence of DCIS significantly affects the accuracy of measuring the sizes of malignant breast tumors when using either B-mode ultrasonography or real time elastography.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22988516</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>The effect of accompanying in situ ductal carcinoma on accuracy of measuring malignant breast tumor size using B-mode ultrasonography and real-time sonoelastography.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Introduction. Despite advances in breast cancer systemic treatment, new prognostic and predictive factors are still needed. Tissue inhibitor of metalloproteinase-1 (TIMP-1), a physiologic inhibitor of matrix metalloproteinases (MMPs), can act in both pro- and antitumoral effects. As role of TIMP-1 in breast cancer is controversial, we aimed to determine the prognostic significance of TIMP-1 in breast cancer. Methods. A single center-based case-control study was applied. Primary breast cancers from women with early stage disease treated with standard adjuvant therapy were analyzed by gene expression microarrays and immunohistochemistry for TIMP-1. Results. At the optimized cut-point, patients with high TIMP-1 RNA levels had a significantly shorter time to relapse, with a hazard ratio (HR) of 1.64 (P = 0.04), but without significant differences in overall survival (HR 1.29, P = 0.37). Although cytoplasmic overexpression of TIMP-1 protein was not correlated with early relapse (HR 1.0, P = 0.92), there was a tendency for short overall survival in patients with high expression (HR 1.41, P = 0.21). Conclusions. Our data indicate that elevated TIMP-1 RNA levels are independently prognostic for early recurrence, and there is a tendency for association of high cytoplasmic TIMP-1 protein levels with short survival in primary breast cancer.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22988515</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Prognostic significance of tissue inhibitor of metalloproteinase-1 in breast cancer.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Ductal carcinoma in situ (DCIS) of the breast is a heterogeneous neoplasm with invasive potential. Risk factors include age, family history, hormone replacement therapy, genetic mutation, and patient lifestyle. The incidence of DCIS has increased due to more widespread use of screening and diagnostic mammography; almost 80% of cases are diagnosed with imaging with final diagnosis established by biopsy and histological examination. There are various classification systems used for DCIS, the most recent of which is based on the presence of intraepithelial neoplasia of the ductal epithelium (DIN). A number of molecular assays are now available that can identify high-risk patients as well as help establish the prognosis of patients with diagnosed DCIS. Current surgical treatment options include total mastectomy, simple lumpectomy in very low-risk patients, and lumpectomy with radiation. Adjuvant therapy is tailored based on the molecular profile of the neoplasm and can include aromatase inhibitors, anti-estrogen, anti-progesterone (or a combination of antiestrogen and antiprogesterone), and HER2 neu suppression therapy. Chemopreventive therapies are under investigation for DCIS, as are various molecular-targeted drugs. It is anticipated that new biologic agents, when combined with hormonal agents such as SERMs and aromatase inhibitors, may one day prevent all forms of breast cancer.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22988495</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Ductal carcinoma in situ of the breast: a surgical perspective.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Vitamin D is characterized as a regulator of homeostasis of bone and mineral metabolism, but it can also provide nonskeletal actions because vitamin D receptors have been found in various tissues including the brain, prostate, breast, colon, pancreas, and immune cells. Bone metabolism, modulation of the immune response, and regulation of cell proliferation and differentiation are all biological functions of vitamin D. Vitamin D may play an important role in modifying the risk of cardiometabolic outcomes, including diabetes mellitus (DM), hypertension, and cardiovascular disease. The incidence of type 2 DM is increasing worldwide and results from a lack of insulin or inadequate insulin secretion following increases in insulin resistance. Therefore, it has been proposed that vitamin D deficiency plays an important role in insulin resistance resulting in diabetes. The potential role of vitamin D deficiency in insulin resistance has been proposed to be associated with inherited gene polymorphisms including vitamin D-binding protein, vitamin D receptor, and vitamin D 1alpha-hydroxylase gene. Other roles have been proposed to involve immunoregulatory function by activating innate and adaptive immunity and cytokine release, activating inflammation by upregulation of nuclear factor κB and inducing tumor necrosis factor α, and other molecular actions to maintain glucose homeostasis and mediate insulin sensitivity by a low calcium status, obesity, or by elevating serum levels of parathyroid hormone. These effects of vitamin D deficiency, either acting in concert or alone, all serve to increase insulin resistance. Although there is evidence to support a relationship between vitamin D status and insulin resistance, the underlying mechanism requires further exploration. The purpose of this paper was to review the current information available concerning the role of vitamin D in insulin resistance.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22988423</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Role of vitamin d in insulin resistance.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Limited guidelines exist for breast cancer management in developing countries. In this context, the Women's Cancer Initiative - Tata Memorial Hospital (WCI-TMH) organised its 8(th) Annual Conference to update guidelines in breast cancer.Appropriately formulated guideline questions on each topic and subtopic in the surgical, radiation and systemic management of primary breast cancer were developed by the scientific committee and shared with the guest faculty of the Conference. Majority of the questions had multiple choice answers. The opinion of the audience, comprising academic and community oncologists, was electronically cumulated, followed by focussed presentations by eminent national and international experts on each topic. The guidelines were finally developed through an expert panel that voted on each guideline question after all talks had been delivered and audience opinion elicited. Separate panels were constituted for locoregional and systemic therapy in primary breast cancer.Based on the voting results of the expert panel, guidelines for locoregional therapy of breast cancer have been formulated. Voting patterns for each question are reported.The updated guidelines on locoregional management of primary breast cancer in the context of developing countries are presented in this article. These recommendations have been designed to allow centers in the developing world to improve the quality of care for breast cancer patients.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22988354</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Guidelines for locoregional therapy in primary breast cancer in developing countries: The results of an expert panel at the 8(th) Annual Women's Cancer Initiative - Tata Memorial Hospital (WCI-TMH) Conference.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>The mTOR pathway is becoming increasingly important in several cancers including breast cancer. This review will focus on the role of its inhibition in the management of advanced breast cancer.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22988350</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>mTOR inhibition in management of advanced breast cancer.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Fibroblast growth factor receptor 2 (FGFR2) has been identified in genome-wide association studies to be associated with increased breast cancer risk, however its mechanism of action remains unclear. Here we show that the two major FGFR2 alternatively spliced isoforms FGFR2-IIIb and FGFR2-IIIc interact with IKKβ and its downstream target NF-κβ. FGFR2 inhibits nuclear RelA/p65 NF-κβ translocation and activity, and reduces expression of dependent transcripts including Interleukin-6. These interactions result in diminished STAT3 phosphorylation and reduced breast cancer cell growth, motility, and invasiveness. FGFR2 also arrests epithelial-to-mesenchymal transition (EMT), resulting in attenuated neoplastic growth in orthotopic xenografts of breast cancer cells. Our studies provide strong evidence for tumor protective effects of FGFR2. We propose that FGFR2 serves as a scaffold for multiple components of the NF-κβ signaling complex. Through these interactions, FGFR2 isoforms can respond to tissue-specific FGF signals to modulate epithelial-stromal communications in cancer progression.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22988296</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>The Breast Cancer Susceptibility Gene FGFR2 Serves as a Scaffold for Regulation of NF-κβ Signaling.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>The literature on breast cancer inevitably includes age as a risk factor for the disease, and there is considerable controversy regarding the best age for women to start screening mammography. A woman's breast develops and changes over the course of her lifetime, and at various times is more or less susceptible to cancer. Developmental differences also affect breast imaging. This article focuses on the age groups outside the majority of women who receive breast cancer diagnoses, instead emphasizing effects of age on the very youngest and oldest women.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22988279</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Breast Cancer: Age-related Factors.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Background Early detection and diagnosis of malignant breast lesions are vital to survival. Although current imaging modalities such as mammography, ultrasonography, and magnetic resonance imaging focus on an anatomic approach, they do not provide sufficient data about the pathophysiology of malignant breast lesions. Positron emission mammography (PEM) is an innovative technology specifically designed to visualize the physiologic and metabolic processes in malignant breast lesions, but it remains underused as a diagnostic tool. Objective The purpose of this research is to provide quantitative and qualitative evidence from radiologists' perspective about the efficacy of physiologic imaging and the future implementation of PEM as a diagnostic tool in clinical practice. Methods Radiologists were asked to complete a survey designed to elicit their perspective on the role of physiologic imaging in detecting and diagnosing breast cancer and on PEM as an adjunct modality. Results Based on the survey data, 66% of participants considered physiologic imaging to be beneficial because it provides additional diagnostic data, and 67% supported the future use of PEM as an adjunct to mammography. Conclusion Although preliminary indications favor the use of adjunct PEM, further research is needed before it becomes a common clinical tool.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22988260</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Radiologist views of positron emission mammography.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
 </object>
</java>