<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<java version="1.7.0_01" class="java.beans.XMLDecoder">
 <object class="biowizard.dict.ArticlesList">
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>This study was performed to evaluate the change in the lumpectomy cavity volumes before and after whole breast radiation therapy (WBRT) and to identify factors associated with the change of volume.From September 2009 to April 2010, the computed tomography (CT) simulation data from 70 patients obtained before and after WBRT was evaluated. The lumpectomy cavity volumes were contoured based on surgical clips, seroma, and postoperative changes. Significant differences in the data from pre-WBRT CT and post-WBRT CT were assessed. Multiple variables were examined for correlation with volume reduction in the lumpectomy cavity.The mean and median volume reduction in the lumpectomy cavity after WBRT were 17.6 cm(3) and 16.1 cm(3), respectively with the statistical significance (p < 0.001). The volume reduction in the lumpectomy cavity was inversely correlated with time from surgery to radiation therapy (R = 0.390). The presence of seroma was significantly associated with a volumetric change in the lumpectomy cavity after WBRT (p = 0.011).The volume of lumpectomy cavity reduced significantly after WBRT. As the time from surgery to the start of WBRT increased, the volume reduction in the lumpectomy cavity during WBRT decreased. A strong correlation was observed between the presence of seroma and the reduced volume. To ensure appropriate coverage and to limit normal tissue exposure during boost irradiation in patients who has seroma at the time of starting WBRT, repeating CT simulation at boost planning is suggested.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22984681</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Volumetric changes in the lumpectomy cavity during whole breast irradiation after breast conserving surgery.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Some women in rural Pakistan are chronically undernourished, and consequently underweight. Concerns have been expressed that the degree of undernourishment might be sufficiently severe to affect lactation performance. We have obtained data on maternal body composition and infant breast milk intake using stable isotope methods in a group of thirty three mother and infant pairs at approximately six months of age. The maternal body mass index ranged from 16.6 to 29.1 kg·m(-2). In this population we found that exclusive breast-feeding tended to be associated with lower maternal body fat, and that there was no evidence for compromised lactational performance due to malnourishment. Finally we note that when our data is combined with that from other studies there may be a generalised negative correlation between breast milk intake and maternal body fat.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22984646</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Maternal Body Composition and Its Relationship to Infant Breast Milk Intake in Rural Pakistan.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Calcitriol antiproliferative effects include inhibition of the oncogenic ether-à-go-go-1 potassium channel (Eag1) expression, which is necessary for cell cycle progression and tumorigenesis. Astemizole, a new promising antineoplastic drug, targets Eag1 by blocking ion currents. Herein, we characterized the interaction between calcitriol and astemizole as well as their conjoint antiproliferative action in SUM-229PE, T-47D and primary tumor-derived breast cancer cells.Molecular markers were studied by immunocytochemistry, Western blot and real time PCR. Inhibitory concentrations were determined by dose-response curves and metabolic activity assays. At clinically achievable drug concentrations, synergistic antiproliferative interaction was observed between calcitriol and astemizole, as calculated by combination index analysis (CI <1). Astemizole significantly enhanced calcitriol's growth-inhibitory effects (3-11 folds, P<0.01). Mean IC(20) values were 1.82±2.41 nM and 1.62±0.75 µM; for calcitriol (in estrogen receptor negative cells) and astemizole, respectively. Real time PCR showed that both drugs alone downregulated, while simultaneous treatment further reduced Ki-67 and Eag1 gene expression (P<0.05). Astemizole inhibited basal and calcitriol-induced CYP24A1 and CYP3A4 mRNA expression (cytochromes involved in calcitriol and astemizole degradation) in breast and hepatoma cancer cells, respectively, while upregulated vitamin D receptor (VDR) expression.Astemizole synergized calcitriol antiproliferative effects by downregulating CYP24A1, upregulating VDR and targeting Eag1. This study provides insight into the molecular mechanisms involved in astemizole-calcitriol combined antineoplastic effect, offering scientific support to test both compounds in combination in further preclinical and clinical studies of neoplasms expressing VDR and Eag1. VDR-negative tumors might also be sensitized to calcitriol antineoplastic effects by the use of astemizole. Herein we suggest a novel combined adjuvant therapy for the management of VDR/Eag1-expressing breast cancer tumors. Since astemizole improves calcitriol bioavailability and activity, decreased calcitriol dosing is advised for conjoint administration.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22984610</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Astemizole Synergizes Calcitriol Antiproliferative Activity by Inhibiting CYP24A1 and Upregulating VDR: A Novel Approach for Breast Cancer Therapy.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Lysosome-associated protein transmembrane 4 beta (LAPTM4B) has two alleles named LAPTM4B*1 and LAPTM4B*2. Allele *1 contains only one copy of a 19-bp sequence at the 5'UTR in the first exon, whereas this sequence of allele*2 is duplicated and arrayed as a tandem repeat. Previous studies revealed that LAPTM4B polymorphisms contribute to the risk of certain types of cancers. This study aimed to investigate the polymorphism of LAPTM4B in breast cancer by analysis the correlation of LAPTM4B genotype with breast cancer susceptibility, clinicopathologic features and prognosis.Genotyping of the LAPTM4B polymorphism was determined by PCR method. The expression levels of LAPTM4B in breast cancer tissues and breast cancer cell lines were determined by quantitative reverse-transcription PCR (qRT-PCR) analysis. The correlation of LAPTM4B genotype with clinicopathologic parameters and prognosis were assessed statistically.The results of qRT-PCR analysis indicated that LAPTM4B*2 was associated with the higher level of LAPTM4B expression compared with the LAPTM4B*1 in both breast cancer cell lines and breast cancer tissues. We found that LAPTM4B*2 was associated with an increased risk for breast cancer. LAPTM4B*2 was significantly associated with higher histopathologic grade, lymph node metastasis and poor prognosis.LAPTM4B*2 is a risk factor associated with breast cancer susceptibility and poor prognosis. LAPTM4B*2 may be a potential predicative marker for the susceptibility, progression and metastasis of breast cancer.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22984585</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>LAPTM4B Allele *2 Is Associated with Breast Cancer Susceptibility and Prognosis.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>There is substantial evidence indicating that the WNT signaling pathway is activated in various cancer cell types including breast cancer. Previous studies reported that FH535, a small molecule inhibitor of the WNT signaling pathway, decreased growth of cancer cells but not normal fibroblasts, suggesting this pathway plays a role in tumor progression and metastasis. In this study, we tested FH535 as a potential inhibitor for malignant phenotypes of breast cancer cells including migration, invasion, and growth. FH535 significantly inhibited growth, migration, and invasion of triple negative (TN) breast cancer cell lines (MDA-MB231 and HCC38) in vitro. We demonstrate that FH535 was a potent growth inhibitor for TN breast cancer cell lines (HCC38 and MDA-MB-231) but not for other, non-TN breast cancer cell lines (MCF-7, T47D or SK-Br3) when cultured in three dimensional (3D) type I collagen gels. Western blotting analyses suggest that treatment of MDA-MB-231 cells with FH535 markedly inhibited the expression of NEDD9 but not activations of FAK, Src, or downstream targets such as p38 and Erk1/2. We demonstrated that NEDD9 was specifically associated with CSPG4 but not with β1 integrin or CD44 in MDA-MB-231 cells. Analyses of gene expression profiles in breast cancer tissues suggest that CSPG4 expression is higher in Basal-type breast cancers, many of which are TN, than any other subtypes. These results suggest not only a mechanism for migration and invasion involving the canonical WNT-signaling pathways but also novel strategies for treating patients who develop TN breast cancer.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22984505</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>FH535 Inhibited Migration and Growth of Breast Cancer Cells.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>To date, risk profiles based on the known common susceptibility variants have limited value in predicting risk of disease but they could be used for risk stratification in prevention programmes at population level. We illustrate the potential utility of polygenic risk stratification using the case of population-based screening for prostate and breast cancer. We compared the number of individuals eligible for screening and the number of cases potentially detectable by screening in a population undergoing screening based on age alone with a population undergoing stratified screening based on age and polygenic risk profile. Stratified screening strategy based on age and genetic risk would potentially improve the efficiency of screening programmes and reduce their adverse consequences. Organisational, ethical, legal and social issues need to be addressed before stratified screening programmes could be implemented.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22984365</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Population-based screening in the era of genomics.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string></string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22984197</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Understanding Breast Density and Breast Cancer Risk.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>OBJECTIVE: To evaluate the efficacy and safety of golimumab 50 and 100 mg monotherapy in Japanese patients with active rheumatoid arthritis (RA) despite treatment with disease-modifying antirheumatic drugs (DMARDs). METHODS: A total of 316 patients were randomised to receive subcutaneous injections every 4 weeks of placebo (group 1), golimumab 50 mg (group 2) or golimumab 100 mg (group 3); group 1 crossed over to golimumab 50 mg at week 16. The primary end point was the proportion of patients achieving ≥20% improvement in the American College of Rheumatology criteria (ACR20) at week 14. ACR50 and ACR70 response rates were also measured. Adverse events (AEs) were monitored throughout the study. RESULTS: Demographics were similar across groups; the mean age was 52 years and 81.8% of patients (252/308) were female. Week 14 ACR20 response rates were significantly greater in groups 2 (51/101 (50.5%)) and 3 (60/102 (58.8%)) than in group 1 (20/105 (19.0%); p<0.0001 for both), as were ACR50 and ACR70 response rates. After placebo crossover at week 16, week 24 ACR response rates were similar in groups 1 and 2. Through week 16, 63.8% of patients in group 1, 62.4% in group 2 and 60.8% in group 3 had AEs and 1.9%, 1.0% and 2.0% had serious AEs. After week 16, one malignancy was reported (breast cancer, group 3). Infections were the most common AEs. No deaths or cases of tuberculosis were reported through week 24. CONCLUSIONS: Golimumab monotherapy (50 and 100 mg) was effective in reducing the signs and symptoms of RA in Japanese patients with active disease despite DMARD treatment.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22984173</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Golimumab monotherapy in Japanese patients with active rheumatoid arthritis despite prior treatment with disease-modifying antirheumatic drugs: results of the phase 2/3, multicentre, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled GO-MONO study through 24 weeks.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>BACKGROUND:Bilateral breast augmentation is an increasingly popular day-case procedure. Local infiltration with sedation is routinely used for its ease of application compared with the more complex and potentially riskier paravertebral blockade (PVB). We hypothesized that ropivacaine injected by experienced anesthesia providers into the paravertebral space as a PVB was more effective than ropivacaine injected by the operating surgeon (plastic surgeon) directly into the zone of surgical dissection.METHODS:Forty female patients who were ASA physical status I or II and undergoing bilateral subpectoral cosmetic breast augmentation were recruited for participation in a prospective, randomized, single-blind study. Patients were randomized to 1 of 2 groups: ropivacaine via PVB, or surgical infiltration of ropivacaine. In both groups, the surgeon was asked to infiltrate the appropriate area with either saline (PVB group) or ropivacaine (local infiltration group). Both groups were sedated with propofol, titrated to effect. The plastic surgeon was blinded to the solution injected. Data collected included demographic characteristics, intraoperative cooperation scores, recovery room postoperative nausea and vomiting, analgesia use, and visual analog scale pain scores. All patients were asked to complete a preoperative anxiety and quality of recovery questionnaire and to record their pain scores and analgesia requirements on discharge. The outcome measures were (i) intraoperative patient cooperation as assessed by the plastic surgeon, (ii) propofol requirement, (iii) postoperative pain, and (iv) quality of recovery.RESULTS:Forty patients completed the study. PVB improved intraoperative cooperation (significance of difference P < 0.001, WMWodds = 6.69 with 95% 1-sided confidence interval CI ≥2.85), reduced propofol requirement (significance of difference P = 0.005, WMWodds = 0.35, CI ≤0.69), and decreased average postoperative pain in the home environment (significance of difference P = 0.007, WMWodds = 0.38, CI ≤0.73). There were no PVB complications. Only patients from the surgical infiltration group required rescue analgesics (30%, significance of difference = 0.01).CONCLUSIONS:In a limited number of patients, we found that PVB is superior to direct surgical infiltration of ropivacaine for bilateral breast augmentation in same-day surgery. These advantages need to be balanced against the potential risks of PVB, especially in an office setting.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22984150</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Paravertebral Blockade for Day-Case Breast Augmentation: A Randomized Clinical Trial.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Neoadjuvant chemotherapy in breast cancer patients aims at preoperative reduction of tumor volume for better resection results and prognosis. As not all patients respond to neoadjuvant therapy, predictive biomarkers are needed for more efficient individual management. In prospectively collected sera of 51 consecutive locally confined breast cancer (LBC) patients receiving preoperative, neoadjuvant chemotherapy, value level kinetics of soluble high mobility group box 1 (HMGB1), soluble receptor for advanced glycation end products (sRAGE) as well as the established breast cancer biomarkers CA 15-3 and carcinoembryonic antigen (CEA) were investigated and correlated with therapy response objectified by pathological staging at surgery. In addition, biomarkers were measured in sera of 30 healthy controls (HC), 13 patients with benign breast diseases, and 28 metastatic breast cancer (MBC) patients. Pretherapeutic levels of soluble HMGB1 were decreased in MBC, while sRAGE was already decreased in LBC. In contrast, CA 15-3 and CEA were strongly elevated in MBC, but not in LBC. Combination of sRAGE and CA 15-3 enabled best discrimination of LBC from HC (AUC 78.2 %; sens 58 % at 95 % spec), while CA15-3 and CEA discriminated best between MBC and all controls (AUC 90.9 %; sens 70 % at 95 % spec). In LBC patients undergoing neoadjuvant chemotherapy, nine patients achieved complete remission (CR), 29 achieved partial remission (PR), while 13 had no change of disease (NC). NC patients tended to have higher HMGB1 and lower sRAGE levels before therapy onset (p = 0.056 and p = 0.054), while CA 15-3 and CEA did not predict therapeutic outcome. Furthermore, kinetics of HMGB1 during therapy correlated with efficacy of the treatment (p = 0.053). Markers of immunogenic cell death are valuable for the diagnosis of MBC and early estimation of response to neoadjuvant therapy in LBC patients.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22983919</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Circulating immunogenic cell death biomarkers HMGB1 and RAGE in breast cancer patients during neoadjuvant chemotherapy.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string></string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22983870</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Close association between genotypes of the Val158Met polymorphism and pain perception in pain patients besides breast cancer patients.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Dietary nutrients are essential for gastrointestinal (GI) growth and function, and nutritional support of GI growth and development is a significant component of infant care. For healthy full-term neonates, nutritional provisions of the mother's milk and/or formula will support normal maturation of structure and function of the GI tract in most infants. The composition of breast milk affects GI barrier function and development of a competent mucosal immune system. The functional nutrients and other bioactive components of milk support a microenvironment for gut protection and maturation. However, premature infants struggle with feeding tolerance impairing normal GI function, leading to intestinal dysfunction and even death. The high prevalence worldwide of enteric diseases and dysfunction in neonates has led to much interest in understanding the role of nutrients and food components in the establishment and maintenance of a functioning GI tract. Neonates who do not receive enteral feeding as either mother's milk or formula are supported by total parental nutrition (TPN). The lack of enteral nutrition can compound intestinal dysfunction, leading to high morbidity and mortality in intestinally compromised infants. Reciprocally, enteral stimulation of an immature GI tract can also compound intestinal dysfunction. Therefore, further understanding of nutrient interactions with the mucosa is necessary to define nutritional requirements of the developing GI tract to minimize intestinal complications and infant morbidity. Piglet models of intestinal development and function are similar to humans, and this review summarizes recent findings regarding nutrient requirements for growth and maintenance of intestinal health. In particular, this article reviews the role of specific amino acids (arginine, glutamine, glutamate, and threonine), fatty acids (long chain polyunsaturated, medium chain, and short chain), various prebiotic carbohydrates (short-chain fructo-oligosaccharide, fructo--oligosaccharide, lacto-N-neotetraose, human milk oligosaccharide, polydextrose, and galacto-oligosaccharide), and probiotics that have been examined in the suckling piglet model of intestinal health.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22983847</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Nutritional factors influencing intestinal health of the neonate.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Emerging evidence suggests that dietary rice bran may exert beneficial effects against several types of cancer, such as breast, lung, liver, and colorectal cancer. The chemopreventive potential has been related to the bioactive phytochemicals present in the bran portion of the rice such as ferulic acid, tricin, β-sitosterol, γ-oryzanol, tocotrienols/tocopherols, and phytic acid. Studies have shown that the anticancer effects of the rice bran-derived bioactive components are mediated through their ability to induce apoptosis, inhibit cell proliferation, and alter cell cycle progression in malignant cells. Rice bran bioactive components protect against tissue damage through the scavenging of free radicals and the blocking of chronic inflammatory responses. Rice bran phytochemicals have also been shown to activate anticancer immune responses as well as affecting the colonic tumor microenvironment in favor of enhanced colorectal cancer chemoprevention. This is accomplished through the modulation of gut microflora communities and the regulation of carcinogen-metabolizing enzymes. In addition, the low cost of rice production and the accessibility of rice bran make it an appealing candidate for global dietary chemoprevention. Therefore, the establishment of dietary rice bran as a practical food-derived chemopreventive agent has the potential to have a significant impact on cancer prevention for the global population.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22983843</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Chemopreventive properties of dietary rice bran: current status and future prospects.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Accelerated partial breast radiotherapy (RT) strategies (3-D conformal external-beam RT (3-D CRT) and brachytherapy with balloon catheter) reduce time and transportation burdens of whole breast RT for breast cancer. Long-term clinical trial evidence is unavailable for accelerated modalities, but uncertainty might be acceptable for patients likely to receive suboptimal whole breast RT. The objective of this study is to assess the cost effectiveness of accelerated partial breast RT compared to on-time and delayed whole breast RT. The design used in this study is decision analytic Markov model. The data sources are published literature; and national/federal sources. The target population of this study is a hypothetical cohort of 60 years old women previously treated with breast-conserving surgery for node-negative, estrogen receptor-positive breast cancer with tumors <1 cm. The time horizon is 15 years, and the perspective is societal. The interventions are whole breast RT, 3-D CRT, and brachytherapy breast irradiation. The outcome measures are costs (2008 US$), quality-adjusted life years (QALYs), and incremental cost-effectiveness ratios. The base-case results were: 3-D CRT was the preferred strategy, costing on average $10,800 and yielding 11.21 QALYs. On-time whole breast RT costs $368,000/QALY compared to 3-D CRT, above the $100,000/QALY WTP threshold. 3-D CRT was also preferred over delayed whole breast RT. Brachytherapy was never preferred. Sensitivity analysis indicated that the results were sensitive to the rate of recurrence outside the initial tumor quadrant ("elsewhere failure") in one-way analysis. Probabilistic sensitivity analysis indicated that results were sensitive to parameter uncertainty, and that the elsewhere-failure rate and treatment preferences may drive results. The limitation of this study is that efficacy estimates are derived from studies that may not fully represent the population modeled. As a conclusion, 3-D CRT was preferred to whole breast RT and for women likely to delay RT, indicating that 3-D CRT could be targeted more efficiently before randomized trial evidence.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22983837</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Cost effectiveness of new breast cancer radiotherapy technologies in diverse populations.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Breast cancer is one of the most common cancers in women worldwide and metastasis is the major cause of breast cancer death. Development of new therapeutic agents for inhibiting breast cancer metastasis is therefore an urgent need. We previously demonstrated that recombinant DNA-derived viral capsid protein VP1 (rVP1) of foot-and-mouth disease virus-induced apoptosis of MCF-7 breast cancer cells in vitro. Here, we investigated whether rVP1 exhibits any inhibitory effects on migration/metastasis and human epidermal growth factor receptor 2 (HER-2), a well-known biomarker for poor prognosis of breast cancer. The effects of rVP1 on cancer cell migration/invasion and metastasis were evaluated using Transwell migration assay and animal cancer models of metastasis. Western blotting, RT-PCR, flow cytometry, immunohistochemistry, and immunofluorescence staining techniques were used to investigate the effects of rVP1 on HER-2 and signal transduction mediators. Non-cytotoxic concentrations of rVP1-induced mesenchymal-epithelial transition and significantly suppressed AP-2α and HER-2 expression as well as the migration and invasion of a variety of breast cancer cell lines in a β1-integrin-dependent manner in vitro. Gross and histopathologic examinations showed that rVP1 also suppressed metastasis of several breast cancer cell lines, including HER-2-overexpressing SK-BR-3 and BT-474 cells to lung, liver, or peripheral lymph node in orthotopic allograft/xenograft murine models. In addition, rVP1 significantly prolonged survival in breast cancer-bearing mice. Notably, no apparent side effects of rVP1 were detected, as shown by normal complete blood count levels and serum biochemistry profiles, including AST, ALT, BUN, and creatine. This study demonstrates that rVP1 suppresses the migration, invasion, and metastasis of breast cancer cells via binding to β1 integrin receptor and down-regulation of AP-2α and HER-2 expression. The effectiveness of rVP1 on inhibiting migration/metastasis of breast cancer and HER-2 expression suggests that it may be suitable for serving as potential therapeutics for metastatic breast cancer particularly HER-2-overexpressing cancer.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22983836</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Recombinant viral protein VP1 suppresses HER-2 expression and migration/metastasis of breast cancer.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Many epidemiological studies have found that leptin correlates to body fat extent and breast cancer. Leptin exerts its physiological action through the leptin receptor (LEPR). However, published data on the association between LEPR alleles and breast cancer occurrence have led to in contradictory results. A total of 10 studies were identified to the meta-analysis, including 4,644 cases and 5,485 controls for LEPR rs1137101 polymorphism, 5 studies with 2,759 cases and 4,464 controls for rs1137100 polymorphism, and 2 studies for rs8051542, rs8051542, and rs8051542 polymorphisms. The pooled odds ratios (OR) with 95 % confidence intervals (CI) for breast cancer risk associated with LEPR genotypes were estimated. Elevated breast cancer risk was associated with LEPR rs1137101 polymorphism when all studies were pooled in the meta-analysis (allele contrast model: OR = 0.71, 95 % CI = 0.551-0.997). In the stratified analysis by ethnicity, significantly increased risks were also found among Asians for allele contrast model (OR 0.414, 95 % CI 0.312-0.550) and dominant model (OR 0.537, 95 % CI 0.370-0.781); for Africans, significantly increased risks were also found for allele contrast model (OR 0.716, 95 % CI 0.595-0.861), homozygote codominant (OR 0.537, 95 % CI 0.370-0.781) and dominant model (OR 1.595, 95 % CI 1.207-2.108). And significantly elevated breast cancer risk was associated with LEPR rs1137100 polymorphism for allele contrast (OR = 0.666, 95 % CI = 0.603-0.720) and homozygote codominant models (OR = 0.344, 95 % CI = 0.282-0.421). For LEPR rs8179183, rs4655537, and rs3762274 polymorphisms, no significant associations were detected in all comparison models. This pooled analysis suggested that rs1137101 and rs1137100 polymorphisms were significantly correlated with breast cancer risk and the A allele of LEPR rs1137101 variant and the G allele of LEPR rs1137100 variant were low-penetrant risk factors for developing breast cancer. Further, no significant associations existed between LEPR rs8179183, rs4655537, and rs3762274 polymorphisms and risk of breast cancer.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22983835</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>The association between polymorphisms in the leptin receptor gene and risk of breast cancer: a systematic review and pooled analysis.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Prediction of resection weight (RW) in reduction mammaplasty is helpful in achieving breast symmetry and in fulfilling the stringent reimbursement requirements of health insurance companies. Current breast volume estimations are largely based on surgeon's experience, which are partially unreliable and often cumbersome to obtain. Therefore, this study aims to develop a formula to predict RW based on 3D surface imaging. A total of 68 breasts were treated with bilateral T-scar, and 40 breasts were treated with bilateral or unilateral vertical-scar reduction mammaplasty. Linear distances and volume measurements were assessed 3-dimensionally preoperatively and 6 months postoperatively. Significant correlations between the RW and the calculated preoperative breast volume (ρ = 0.804) and the sternal notch to nipple distance (ρ = 0.839) were found in both techniques (P < .001). Regression equations with the RW were performed to derive prediction formulas. Surgeons may benefit from the formulas in terms of improvement in preoperative planning, dealing with insurance coverage questions, and optimizing patient consultation.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22983806</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Prediction of Breast Resection Weight in Reduction Mammaplasty Based on 3-Dimensional Surface Imaging.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Breast cancer is a clinically heterogeneous disease characterized by distinct molecular aberrations. Understanding the heterogeneity and identifying subgroups of breast cancer are essential to improving diagnoses and predicting therapeutic responses. In this paper, we propose a classification scheme for breast cancer which integrates data on differentially expressed genes (DEGs), copy number variations (CNVs) and microRNAs (miRNAs)-regulated mRNAs. Pathway information based on the estimation of molecular pathway activity is also applied as a postprocessor to optimize the classifier. A total of 250 malignant breast tumors were analyzed by k-means clustering based on the patterns of the expression profiles of 215 intrinsic genes, and the classification performances were compared with existing breast cancer classifiers including the BluePrint and the 625-gene classifier. We show that a classification scheme which incorporates pathway information with various genetic variations achieves better performance than classifiers based on the expression levels of individual genes, and propose that the identified signature serves as a basic tool for identifying rational therapeutic opportunities for breast cancer patients.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22983731</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>A pathway-based classification of breast cancer integrating data on differentially expressed genes, copy number variations and MicroRNA target genes.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>BACKGROUND: Therapeutic mammaplasty (TM) for breast cancer is a widely practiced oncoplastic technique. Patient selection criteria and method of margin assessment are not clearly established. The aim of our review was to analyse oncological and aesthetic outcomes over a 7 year period. METHODS: We conducted a retrospective review of 251 breast cancer patients who underwent TM from 2002 to 2009 at the Netcare Breast Care Centre, Johannesburg. Primary chemotherapy was used to downsize large tumours. Intraoperative margin assessment was performed. Statistical analysis was performed using Kaplan-Meier estimates. Cosmetic outcomes were assessed by an independent review panel using photographic material. RESULTS: Mean tumour size was 15.4 mm. Mean resection weight was 237 g. Sixty-four (25.5 %) patients received primary chemotherapy. Mean margin taken was 15 mm. The back-to-theatre rate was 2 % (5 cases). A total of 222 patients underwent bilateral procedures. Contralateral occult disease was identified in six cases (2.4 %). The early (<2 months) complication rate was 3.2 %. Late complications were related to adjuvant radiotherapy (20.7 %). Mean follow-up was 50 months. The recurrence rate was 4 %. Five of six patients with locoregional recurrence had DCIS at initial surgery. The mortality rate was 3.2 %. The overall survival rate was 96.4 % and the metastasis-free survival rate was 94.6 %. Acceptable aesthetic results were achieved in 96 % of the patients. CONCLUSIONS: Primary chemotherapy allowed for TM in patients with large tumours. Intraoperative margin assessment decreased reoperation rate. Contralateral matching procedures resulted in histological detection of occult disease. TM is an oncologically appropriate and cosmetically favourable technique.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22983674</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Therapeutic Mammaplasty for Breast Cancer: Oncological and Aesthetic Outcomes.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>The aim of the present research was to study the anticancer effects of Aspergillus niger (A.niger) RNase. We found that RNase (A.niger RNase) significantly and dose dependently inhibited invasiveness of breast cancer cell line MDA MB 231 by 55 % (P < 0.01) at 1 μM concentration. At a concentration of 2 μM, the anti invasive effect of the enzyme increased to 90 % (P < 0.002). Keeping the aim to determine molecular level interactions (molecular simulations and protein docking) of human actin with A.niger RNase we extended our work in-vitro to in-silico studies. To gain better relaxation and accurate arrangement of atoms, refinement was done on the human actin and A.niger RNase by energy minimization (EM) and molecular dynamics (MD) simulations using 43A(2) force field of Gromacs96 implemented in the Gromacs 4.0.5 package, finally the interaction energies were calculated by protein-protein docking using the HEX. These in vitro and in-silico structural studies prove the effective inhibition of actin activity by A.niger RNase in neoplastic cells and thereby provide new insights for the development of novel anti cancer drugs.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22983653</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Molecular docking and dynamics simulations of A.niger RNase from Aspergillus niger ATCC26550: for potential prevention of human cancer.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>BACKGROUND: Worry about cancer progression and perceived social support can affect cancer survivors' quality of life (QOL). METHODS: In 480 early-stage breast cancer survivors, we examined how worry about cancer progression and perceived social support 6 months after definitive surgery were associated with QOL (RAND 36-item Health Survey) at 6-, 12-, and 24-month follow-up. RESULTS: At 6 months post-surgery, higher worry was associated with worse QOL for five of eight subscales. Lower social support was associated with worse QOL for four subscales. The negative effects of worry and limited social support dissipated for four subscales (worry) and two subscales (social support) by 12-month follow-up and for all subscales by 24-month follow-up. Social support at 6 months moderated the relationship between T2 worry and T4 emotional well-being; post hoc tests did not clarify the nature of the interaction. CONCLUSION: Early-stage breast cancer survivors who worry about cancer progression and/or have low social support may experience lower levels of QOL that can take several months to resolve.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22983622</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Worry About Cancer Progression and Low Perceived Social Support: Implications for Quality of Life Among Early-Stage Breast Cancer Patients.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>The PI3K-Akt pathway is a vital regulator of cell proliferation and survival. Alterations in the PIK3CA gene that lead to enhanced PI3K kinase activity have been reported in many human cancer types, including cancers of the colon, breast, brain, liver, stomach and lung. Deregulation of PI3K causes aberrant Akt activity. Therefore targeting this pathway could have implications for cancer treatment. The first generation PI3K-Akt inhibitors were proven to be highly effective with a low IC(50), but later, they were shown to have toxic side effects and poor pharmacological properties and selectivity. Thus, these inhibitors were only effective in preclinical models. However, derivatives of these first generation inhibitors are much more selective and are quite effective in targeting the PI3K-Akt pathway, either alone or in combination. These second-generation inhibitors are essentially a specific chemical moiety that helps to form a strong hydrogen bond interaction with the PI3K/Akt molecule. The goal of this review is to delineate the current efforts that have been undertaken to inhibit the various components of the PI3K and Akt pathway in different types of cancer both in vitro and in vivo. Our focus here is on these novel therapies and their inhibitory effects that depend upon their chemical nature, as well as their development towards clinical trials.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22983389</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>PI3K and Akt as molecular targets for cancer therapy: current clinical outcomes.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>ABSTRACT: Globally, low birth weight (LBW) is a major factor contributing to stunting, the most common form of childhood malnutrition, and both are associated with substantial mortality and disease burden. To reduce the burden of LBW and stunting, national governments should play effective roles through multi-sectoral collaboration with strong political commitment to ensure nationwide coverage of direct or nutrition-specific interventions and indirect or nutrition-sensitive interventions. The former include interventions such as breast feeding, complementary feeding, micronutrient supplementation, treatment of acute malnutrition, etc. Indirect interventions include improving agricultural crop yield as well as food diversity, creating livelihoods, increasing literacy, and empowering women, etc.There is no single remedy for stunting; comprehensive implementation of basic nutrition interventions should reduce the burden of stunting. Severe acute malnutrition (SAM) kills 1 million children each year in 20 countries across Africa, Asia, Western Pacific and the Middle East. Facility-based treatment is available in some countries but is expensive, inconvenient to family as it requires lengthy hospitalizations and its outreach is limited. Community-based management of SAM can complement facility-based treatment by expanding the outreach, curtailing facility expenses and allowing treatment at home thereby decreasing the burden on families. This, however, has to be tagged with interventions that prevent malnutrition. The prevalence of childhood obesity is rapidly growing in developing countries and is a priority requiring action. Finally applied research should focus on the effectiveness of intervention strategies whereas basic research is required in the interaction between nutrition and human microbiome, and conditions such as environmental enteropathy.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22983380</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Malnutrition Report of the FISPGHAN Working Group.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>The novel steroidal conjugates [M(η(5)-C(5)Me(5))Cl(LEV-ppy)] (M = Rh () and Ir ()) bearing the lipophilic levonorgestrel group 17-α-[2-phenylpyridyl-4-ethynyl]-19-nortestosterone (LEV-ppy), where the chelating ligand is N and C-bound, have been prepared and characterized. Both compounds are more active than cisplatin (about 6-fold) in T47D (breast cancer) at 48 h incubation time. On the other hand, very low resistance factors (RF) of and in A2780cisR (cisplatin-resistant ovarian carcinoma) at 48 h were observed (RF = 0.9 and 1.1, respectively). The iridium steroidal compound is twice as active as the non-steroidal analogue , whose promising anticancer activity has recently been reported by Sadler. Theoretical DFT calculations on complexes and at the B3LYP-D/def2-TZVP-ecp level of theory show that the strongest bond to the metal atom is the η(5)-interaction to the Cp* ligand and that both of them feature a rather strong metal-chlorine bond. The new steroidal conjugates and are able to bind to DNA according to Hoechst 33258 displacement experiments and ESI-TOF MS spectrometry studies. Complexes and are also cathepsin B inhibitors, an enzyme implicated in a number of cancer related events.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22983366</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Novel C,N-chelate rhodium(iii) and iridium(iii) antitumor complexes incorporating a lipophilic steroidal conjugate and their interaction with DNA.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>The human CYP3A subfamily plays a dominant role in the metabolic elimination of more drugs than any other biotransformation enzyme. CYP3A enzyme is localized in the liver and small intestine and thus contributes to first-pass and systemic metabolism. CYP3A expression varies as much as 40-fold in liver and small intestine donor tissues. CYP3Adependent in vivo drug clearance appears to be unimodally distributed which suggests multi-genic or complex gene-environment causes of variability. Interindividual differences in enzyme expression may be due to several factors including: variable homeostatic control mechanisms, disease states that alter homeostasis, up- or down-regulation by environmental stimuli (such as smoking, drug intake, or diet), and genetic mutations. This review summarizes the current understanding and implications of genetic variation in the CYP3A enzymes. Unlike other human P450s (CYP2D6, CYP2C19) there is no evidence of a 'null' allele for CYP3A4. More than 30 SNPs (single nucleotide polymorphisms) have been identified in the CYP3A4 gene. Generally, variants in the coding regions of CYP3A4 occur at allele frequencies ,5% and appear as heterozygous with the wild-type allele. These coding variants may contribute to but are not likely to be the major cause of inter-individual differences in CYP3A-dependent clearance, because of the low allele frequencies and limited alterations in enzyme expression or catalytic function. The most common variant, CYP3A4*1B, is an A-392G transition in the 59-flanking region with an allele frequency ranging from 0% (Chinese and Japanese) to 45% (African-Americans). Studies have not linked CYP3A4*1B with alterations in CYP3A substrate metabolism. In contrast, there are several reports about its association with various disease states including prostate cancer, secondary leukemias, and early puberty. Linkage disequilibrium between CYP3A4*1B and another CYP3A allele (CYP3A5*1 ) may be the true cause of the clinical phenotype. CYP3A5 is polymorphically expressed in adults with readily detectable expression in about 10-20% in Caucasians, 33% in Japanese and 55% in African-Americans. The primary causal mutation for its polymorphic expression (CYP3A5*3 ) confers low CYP3A5 protein expression as a result of improper mRNA splicing and reduced translation of a functional protein. The CYP3A5*3 allele frequency varies from approximately 50% in African-Americans to 90% in Caucasians. Functionally, microsomes from a CYP3A5*3 /*3 liver contain very low CYP3A5 protein and display on average reduced catalytic activity towards midazolam. Additional intronic or exonic mutations (CYP3A5*5, *6, and *7 ) may alter splicing and result in premature stop codons or exon deletion. Several CYP3A5 coding variants have been described, but occur at relatively low allelic frequencies and their functional significance has not been established. As CYP3A5 is the primary extrahepatic CYP3A isoform, its polymorphic expression may be implicated in disease risk and the metabolism of endogenous steroids or xenobiotics in these tissues (e.g., lung, kidney, prostate, breast, leukocytes). CYP3A7 is considered to be the major fetal liver CYP3A enzyme. Although hepatic CYP3A7 expression appears to be significantly down-regulated after birth, protein and mRNA have been detected in adults. Recently, increased CYP3A7 mRNA expression has been associated with the replacement of a 60-bp segment of the CYP3A7 promoter with a homologous segment in the CYP3A4 promoter (CYP3A7*1C allele). This mutational swap confers increased gene transcription due to an enhanced interaction between activated PXR:RXRa complex and its cognate response element (ER-6). The genetic basis for polymorphic expression of CYP3A5 and CYP3A7 has now been established. Moreover, the substrate specificity and product regioselectivity of these isoforms can differ from that of CYP3A4, such that the impact of CYP3A5 and CYP3A7 polymorphic expression on drug disposition will be drug dependent. In addition to genetic variation, other factors that may also affect CYP3A expression include: tissue-specific splicing (as reported for prostate CYP3A5), variable control of gene transcription by endogenous molecules (circulating hormones) and exogenous molecules (diet or environment), and genetic variations in proteins that may regulate constitutive and inducible CYP3A expression (nuclear hormone receptors). Thus, the complex regulatory pathways, environmentally susceptible milieu of the CYP3A enzymes, and as yet undetermined genetic haplotypes, may confound evaluation of the effect of individual CYP3A genetic variations on drug disposition, efficacy and safety.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22983347</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Genetic contribution to variable human CYP3A-mediated metabolism.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>The receptor for folic acid constitutes a useful target for tumor-specific drug delivery, primarily because: (1) it is upregulated in many human cancers, including malignancies of the ovary, brain, kidney, breast, myeloid cells and lung, (2) access to the folate receptor in those normal tissues that express it can be severely limited due to its location on the apical (externally-facing) membrane of polarized epithelia, and (3) folate receptor density appears to increase as the stage /grade of the cancer worsens. Thus, cancers that are most difficult to treat by classical methods may be most easily targeted with folate-linked therapeutics. To exploit these peculiarities of folate receptor expression, folic acid has been linked to both low molecular weight drugs and macromolecular complexes as a means of targeting the attached molecules to malignant cells. Conjugation of folic acid to macromolecules has been shown to enhance their delivery to folate receptor-expressing cancer cells in vitro in almost all situations tested. Folate-mediated macromolecular targeting in vivo has, however, yielded only mixed results, largely because of problems with macromolecule penetration of solid tumors. Nevertheless, prominent examples do exist where folate targeting has significantly improved the outcome of a macromolecule-based therapy, leading to complete cures of established tumors in many cases. This review presents a brief mechanistic background of folate-targeted macromolecular therapeutics and then summarizes the successes and failures observed with each major application of the technology.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22983320</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Folate-mediated delivery of macromolecular anticancer therapeutic agents.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>OBJECTIVES: To introduce a new three-dimensional (3D) diagnostic imaging technology, termed "multimodal ultrasonic tomography" (MUT), for the detection of breast cancer without ionising radiation or compression. METHODS: MUT performs 3D tomography of the pendulant breast in a water-bath using transmission ultrasound in a fixed-coordinate system. Specialised electronic hardware and signal processing algorithms are used to construct multimodal images for each coronal slice, corresponding to measurements of refractivity and frequency-dependent attenuation and dispersion. In-plane pixel size is 0.25 mm × 0.25 mm and the inter-slice interval can vary from 1 to 4 mm, depending on clinical requirements. MUT imaging was performed on 25 patients ("off-label" use for research purposes only), presenting lesions with sizes >10 mm. Histopathology of biopsy samples, obtained from all patients, were used to evaluate the MUT outcomes. RESULTS: All lesions (21 malignant and four benign) were clearly identified on the MUT images and correctly classified into benign and malignant based on their respective multimodal information. Malignant lesions generally exhibited higher values of refractivity and frequency-dependent attenuation and dispersion. CONCLUSION: Initial clinical results confirmed the ability of MUT to detect and differentiate all suspicious lesions with sizes >10 mm discernible in mammograms of 25 female patients. KEY POINTS: • Technical advances in ultrasound offer new diagnostic opportunities in breast imaging • 3D ultrasound can detect breast cancer without ionising radiation or compression • Multimodal 3D ultrasound assesses acoustic refractivity, frequency-dependent attenuation and dispersion • MUT can differentiate between benign and malignant breast lesions.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22983317</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Novel technology of multimodal ultrasound tomography detects breast lesions.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>OBJECTIVES: To assess whether magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) can identify pre-treatment differences or monitor early response in breast cancer patients receiving neoadjuvant chemotherapy. METHODS: PubMed, Cochrane library, Medline and Embase databases were searched for publications until January 1, 2012. After primary selection, studies were selected based on predefined inclusion/exclusion criteria. Two reviewers assessed study contents using an extraction form. RESULTS: In 15 studies, which were mainly underpowered and of heterogeneous study design, 31 different parameters were studied. Most frequently studied parameters were tumour diameter or volume, K(trans), K(ep), V(e), and apparent diffusion coefficient (ADC). Other parameters were analysed in only two or less studies. Tumour diameter, volume, and kinetic parameters did not show any pre-treatment differences between responders and non-responders. In two studies, pre-treatment differences in ADC were observed between study groups. At early response monitoring significant and non-significant changes for all parameters were observed for most of the imaging parameters. CONCLUSIONS: Evidence on distinguishing responders and non-responders to neoadjuvant chemotherapy using pre-treatment MRI, as well as using MRI for early response monitoring, is weak and based on underpowered study results and heterogeneous study design. Thus, the value of breast MRI for response evaluation has not yet been established. KEY POINTS: • Few well-validated pre-treatment MR parameters exist that identify responders and non-responders. • Eligible studies showed heterogeneous study designs which hampered pooling of data. • Confounders and technical variations of MRI accuracy are not studied adequately. • Value of MRI for response evaluation needs to be established further.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22983282</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Pre-treatment differences and early response monitoring of neoadjuvant chemotherapy in breast cancer patients using magnetic resonance imaging: a systematic review.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string></string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22983174</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Gene transfer of Chlorella vulgaris n-3 fatty acid desaturase optimizes the fatty acid composition of human breast cancer cells.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>PURPOSE: Expression of the adhesion molecule L1-CAM (L1) has been shown to correlate with early recurrence in breast cancer. Here, we investigated whether L1-CAM expression of breast cancer cells might influence adherence to human pulmonary microvascular endothelial cells (HPMEC) and thus promote metastasis. METHODS: MDA-MB231-Fra2 breast cancer cells that express high levels of L1-CAM (L1(high) cells) were stably transfected to generate clones with strong L1-CAM downregulation. Adhesion to activated HPMEC was studied in dynamic cell flow and static assays. Potential binding partners on endothelial cells were identified by blocking experiments and adhesion assays after coating of the flow channels with recombinant proteins. RESULTS: Adhesion of L1(high) cells to activated HPMEC was significantly higher compared to L1l(ow) clones under flow conditions. Blocking experiments and adhesion assays with recombinant proteins identified activated leucocyte cell adhesion molecule (ALCAM) or L1 itself, but not ICAM-1, as potential binding partners on endothelial cells. E-selectin blocking antibodies strongly diminished the adherence of breast cancer cells irrespective of their L1-CAM expression. CONCLUSIONS: Our experiments indicate that L1-CAM expression on breast cancer cells can promote adherence to activated endothelial cells by binding to endothelial L1-CAM or ALCAM. This mechanism might lead to increased metastasis and a poor prognosis in L1-CAM-positive carcinomas in vivo. Therefore, L1-CAM might be a suitable therapeutic target in breast cancers with a high L1-CAM expression.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22983139</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Influence of L1-CAM expression of breast cancer cells on adhesion to endothelial cells.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Impaired DNA damage response pathways may create vulnerabilities of cancer cells that can be exploited therapeutically. One such selective vulnerability is the sensitivity of BRCA1- or BRCA2-defective tumors (hence defective in DNA repair by homologous recombination, HR) to inhibitors of the poly(ADP-ribose) polymerase-1 (PARP-1), an enzyme critical for repair pathways alternative to HR. While promising, treatment with PARP-1 inhibitors (PARP-1i) faces some hurdles, including (1) acquired resistance, (2) search for other sensitizing, non-BRCA1/2 cancer defects and (3) lack of biomarkers to predict response to PARP-1i. Here we addressed these issues using PARP-1i on 20 human cell lines from carcinomas of the breast, prostate, colon, pancreas and ovary. Aberrations of the Mre11-Rad50-Nbs1 (MRN) complex sensitized cancer cells to PARP-1i, while p53 status was less predictive, even in response to PARP-1i combinations with camptothecin or ionizing radiation. Furthermore, monitoring PARsylation and Rad51 foci formation as surrogate markers for PARP activity and HR, respectively, supported their candidacy for biomarkers of PARP-1i responses. As to resistance mechanisms, we confirmed the role of the multidrug resistance efflux transporters and its reversibility. More importantly, we demonstrated that shRNA lentivirus-mediated depletion of 53BP1 in human BRCA1-mutant breast cancer cells increased their resistance to PARP-1i. Given the preferential loss of 53BP1 in BRCA-defective and triple-negative breast carcinomas, our findings warrant assessment of 53BP1 among candidate predictive biomarkers of response to PARPi. Overall, this study helps characterize genetic and functional determinants of cellular responses to PARP-1i and contributes to the search for biomarkers to exploit PARP inhibitors in cancer therapy.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22983061</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Evaluation of candidate biomarkers to predict cancer cell sensitivity or resistance to PARP-1 inhibitor treatment.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Fat necrosis of the breast is a relatively common reactive/reparative process that may be either primary, often after trauma, or secondary to prior surgery or therapeutic irradiation. Mammary fat necrosis may closely mimic breast neoplasia, both clinically and radiographically, and is thus frequently biopsied. In the majority of cases fat necrosis in the breast shows classic morphologic features and is a straightforward diagnosis. However, over the past several years we have seen a number of more challenging cases of mammary fat necrosis complicated by a distinctive cellular, spindled proliferation of macrophages, mimicking various spindle cell neoplasms of the breast. Herein we report our experience with such lesions. A total of 118 cases of fat necrosis involving the breast were retrieved from our institutional and consultation archives for the period 1994 to 2011. The final study group of 20 cases included only (1) consultation cases submitted specifically with concern for a spindle cell neoplasm and (2) institutional cases presenting as a mass lesion and showing an identical spindle cell proliferation. The tumors occurred in 20 women (mean age 58 y; range, 24 to 70 y), involved both breasts (left, 11 cases; right, 9 cases), and ranged in size from 0.8 to 2.5 cm (mean 1.5 cm). Additional clinical information was available for 18 (90%) patients; a history of ipsilateral breast carcinoma and prior therapeutic irradiation were documented in 7 of 18 (39%) and 6 of 18 (33%) patients, respectively. Radiographic reports and/or imaging was available for 17 (85%) patients; radiographic impressions were "suspicious for malignancy" (10 cases, 59%), "indeterminate" (2 cases, 12%), or "benign" (5 cases, 29%). The patients underwent core needle (14 cases, 70%) and excisional (6 cases, 30%) biopsies. The morphologic features of all cases were similar, showing a moderately cellular, fascicular proliferation of mitotically active, normochromatic, lightly eosinophilic spindled cells with mild nuclear variability, folded or grooved nuclei, and indistinct nucleoli. Chronic inflammatory cells and multinucleated giant cells were often admixed with the spindled cells, with more typical features of fat necrosis frequently present at the periphery. Immunohistochemical analysis performed at Mayo Clinic showed the lesional cells to express the histiocyte-associated markers CD163 (8 of 8, 100%), CD11c (8 of 8, 100%), and CD31 (4 of 8, 50%) and to be negative for keratins using the OSCAR monoclonal antibody (0 of 8, 0%). Studies conducted at outside institutions showed absent expression of various keratins, S100 protein, p63, and β-catenin protein. Histochemical staining for mycobacterial and fungal organisms was negative. Follow-up (18 patients, 1 to 120 mo, mean 37 mo) showed all patients to be alive without disease. Additional surgical procedures (6 patients) showed only fat necrosis. We believe that these lesions represent an exaggerated histiocytic reaction to fat necrosis in the breast. Awareness of this distinctive pseudotumor should help to prevent its misdiagnosis as various other mammary spindle cell neoplasms.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22982900</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Cellular spindled histiocytic pseudotumor complicating mammary fat necrosis: a potential diagnostic pitfall.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>: To evaluate the reliability of novel brightfield microscopy-based dual in situ hybridization (BDISH) methods for frontline HER2 status analysis in selected suboptimally preserved breast cancer tissue samples reflecting of the worst scenario in a community.: A total of 320 morphologically poorly preserved breast invasive ductal carcinomas from the archives of 2 tertiary institutions in Brazil were selected for a tissue microarray-based analysis. 4B5 antibody was used for immunohistochemistry. Fluorescence in situ hybridization (FISH), DuoCISH, ZytoDot CISH, and silver in situ hybridization (SISH) were performed and compared. The highest agreement was observed between SISH and FISH. In addition, SISH was easier to assess in both amplified and nonamplified cases when compared with the other chromogenic methods, due to the sharpness of its dots. DuoCISH produced false-positive results, associated with thicker ill-defined dots, causing poor distinction between nonamplification and low amplification. ZytoDot CISH showed lower sensitivity, with increased frequency of false-positive results.: SISH is the most reliable of the BDISH methods, with sensitivity and specificity highly comparable with FISH. It is also less deleterious than other BDISH methods, producing signals that were more distinct and therefore more readily analyzable even in poorly preserved tissue.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22982892</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Evaluation of Reliability of FISH Versus Brightfield Dual-probe In Situ Hybridization (BDISH) for Frontline Assessment of HER2 Status in Breast Cancer Samples in a Community Setting: Influence of Poor Tissue Preservation.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>: A qualitative study finds that young women with a BRCA gene mutation have concerns about marriage and childbearing. OBJECTIVE: Women who carry a BRCA1 or BRCA2 gene mutation face a risk of developing breast or ovarian cancer at an earlier age than women without such a mutation. Relatively little is known about the psychosocial consequences-especially regarding marriage and childbearing-in young women who test positive for one of these mutations. METHODS: In 2006, participants were recruited from Web sites for women with breast cancer or BRCA gene mutations. Forty-four women ages 18 to 39 from 22 states and Canada who had had genetic testing and were found to carry a BRCA mutation were interviewed by phone or e-mail. A qualitative, grounded theory analysis was performed on the data, focusing on the participants' being young and having had genetic testing for the BRCA mutation. The findings reported here focus on three characteristics of the participants-whether or not they were married, had children, or had a breast cancer diagnosis-and how those characteristics were affected by the women's knowledge of their genetic risk. RESULTS: Among the 13 unmarried participants, issues of when to disclose information about their genetic risk in intimate relationships were discussed. Many of the 24 participants who had children reported "staying alive" for their children as a primary goal; the childless women reported an urgency to have children. Of the 21 who had a breast cancer diagnosis, the youngest was 24 years old, and several said knowledge of their genetic risk influenced their decision to have the unaffected breast removed prophylactically. CONCLUSIONS: A sense of being different and not understood was expressed in these interviews. These findings suggest that nurses should be aware of psychosocial issues, especially those surrounding marriage and childbearing, in their interactions with young women who carry a BRCA1 or BRCA2 gene mutation.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22982855</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Being Young, Female, and BRCA Positive.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Objective: Imperforate hymen and vaginal atresia and their associated anomalies commonly present either at puberty or in the newborn period. Our aim was to report the first case of Imperforate hymen and vaginal atresia who presented with mucocolpos during toddlerhood.Methods: We studied an 18 month old girl who presented with appearance of pubic hair who on examination also had breast enlargement. She underwent biochemical evaluation with serum FSH, LH and estrogen and radiological evaluation with sonogram of abdomen/pelvis, MRI of pelvis and brain.Results: She had clinical and imaging findings suggestive of idiopathic central precocious puberty. Imaging also revealed mucocolpos. She underwent surgery to ensure patent vaginal opening before initiation of GnRH analogues since the latter may precipitate uterine bleeding and might have converted mucocolpos to muco/hematocolpos.Conclusion: This case emphasizes the need to suspect precocious puberty in all girls who present with mucocolpos beyond infancy but before adolescence.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22982793</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Mucocolpos in a toddler: central precocious puberty with vaginal atresia.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Medicinal values of mulberry are known to humans from ancient ages. The white mulberry, M. alba L. is a rich source of many bioactive phytochemicals. Earlier investigations in our laboratory lead to the purification and characterization of an anti-proliferative lectin (MLL) from the leaves of this plant. Further to that, here we have investigated the mechanism of cell death induction by MLL on human breast cancer (MCF-7) and colon cancer (HCT-15) cells. Cells were treated with GI(50) concentration (concentration of lectin required for 50% inhibition of cell growth) of MLL (8.5 μg/ml for MCF-7 and 16 μg/ml for HCT-15) for 24 hrs to induce cell death. The induction of apoptosis was studied by morphological analysis, DNA fragmentation, apoptotic cell staining and caspase 3 activity assay. Apoptotic cells in sub G0-G1 phase were monitored using flow cytometry. MLL induced significant morphological changes and DNA fragmentation associated with apoptosis in MCF-7 and HCT-15 cells. Positive annexin V and acridine orange/ethidium bromide stained cells indicated apoptosis induction by MLL. Up-regulation of caspase-3 activity was also found in cells treated with MLL. Flow cytometry analysis showed an increase in the percentage of cells in sub G0-G1 phase confirming the MLL induced apoptosis. In conclusion, MLL induced apoptosis in MCF-7 and HCT-15 cells in a caspase dependent manner.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22982777</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Purified mulberry leaf lectin (MLL) induces apoptosis and cell cycle arrest in human breast cancer and colon cancer cells.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>The fusarielins are a group of metabolites found in several Aspergillus and Fusarium species that have been reported to have with weak antifungal, antibiotic and cytotoxic effects. This study identifies fusarielin A, F, G and H isolated from Fusarium as mycoestrogens. Mycoestrogens are compounds from fungi that bind to the estrogen receptors and induce an estrogenic response in targeted cells. All four tested fusarielins stimulate MCF-7 cell proliferation with fusarielin H as the most potent, able to stimulate cell proliferation four fold in a resazurin metabolism assay at 25μM. MDA-MB-231 cells without the estrogen receptor-α and MCF-10a cells without estrogen receptors were not stimulated by fusarielins. Furthermore, the stimulation was prevented in MCF-7 cells when fusarielins were incubated in presences of the estrogen receptor antagonist fulvestrant. These observations suggest that fusarielins bind to the estrogen receptor and act as weak mycoestrogens.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22982765</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Estrogenic effects of fusarielins in human breast cancer cell lines.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Background: Ubiquitous mitochondrial creatine kinase (uMtCK), a mitochondrial isoenzyme of creatine kinase (CK), is a central controller of cellular energy homeostasis. Overexpression of uMtCK has been reported to be associated with a poor prognosis for several tumors. The aim of this study was to assess its association with breast cancer (BCa) and to further investigate its underlying mechanisms. Method: We first detected uMtCK expression by immunohistochemistry in human BCa tissues and assessed the association with the prognosis of patients. We then evaluated uMtCK expression in crowded and normal condition cultures of several human BCa cell lines. After two stable clones of the MDA-MB-231 cell line with high expression of uMtCK were established, cell growth, apoptosis and mitochondrial apoptotic pathway protein expression were measured in these clones. Finally, tumorigenicity of the above cells was assessed using nude mice to explore the relationship between uMtCK expression and tumor progression. Results: uMtCK expression was detected in 85.5% (47 of 55) of the invasive ductal carcinomas of breast tissue, not otherwise specified (IDC-NOS). Expression in BCa tissue was significantly associated with reduced progression-free survival (PFS; P=0.019) and overall survival (OS; P=0.022) of the patients. Up-regulation of uMtCK expression was identified in crowded BCa cells in culture, and the number of apoptotic cells was significantly decreased in uMtCK transfected MDA-MB-231 cell clones (P<0.01). Stabilization of the mitochondrial membrane potential (ΔΨm) and down regulation of cyt c and activated caspase 9, two components of mitochondrial apoptotic pathway proteins, were also identified in the same clones when cells were crowded in culture. In vivo studies revealed that the transfected tumor cells with uMtCK overexpression induced faster tumor growth in nude mice, along with accelerated animal body weight loss and a significantly lower tumor apoptotic index (AI) (P<0.001). Conclusion: The results indicated that uMtCK expression is associated with a poor prognosis in BCa and might serve as a tumor marker. In vivo and in vitro evidence suggests that uMtCK overexpression promotes tumor growth by inhibiting apoptosis of tumor cells through stabilizing ΔΨm and down regulating mitochondrial apoptotic pathway proteins. Exploration of therapeutic agents targeting the expression of uMtCK may have practical value for BCa patients.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22982673</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Overexpression of ubiquitous mitochondrial creatine kinase (uMtCK) accelerates tumor growth by inhibiting apoptosis of breast cancer cells and is associated with a poor prognosis in breast cancer patients.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Estrogen receptor β is expressed in normal and neoplastic ovarian and endometrial tissues. Recent studies indicate that levels of this receptor decline in ovarian tumorigenesis, like in breast or prostate cancer. Furthermore, ERβ expression has been associated with good prognosis in ovarian cancer. In contrast, previous studies on the role of this receptor in endometrial cancer suggested that ERβ might play different roles in the carcinogenesis of the ovary and endometrium. Besides its possible role as a prognostic factor, ERβ might be a potential target for the treatment of ovarian and endometrial cancer.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22982616</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Role of estrogen receptor β in gynecological cancer.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Assessment of the regional lymphatics is important for accurate staging and treatment of breast cancer patients. We sought to determine the role of regional ultrasound in providing clinically relevant information. We retrospectively analyzed data from patients who were treated curatively in 1996-2006 at The University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center for clinical stage III breast cancer. We compared differences in regional lymph node staging based on ultrasound versus mammography and physical examination in the 865 of 1,200 patients who had external-beam radiation as part of their treatment and regional ultrasound studies as part of their initial evaluation. Ultrasound uniquely identified additional lymph node involvement beyond the level I or II axilla in 37% of the patients (325 of 865), leading to a change in clinical nodal stage. Ninety-one percent of these abnormalities that could be biopsied (266 or 293) were confirmed to contain disease. The sites of additional regional nodal disease were: infraclavicular disease, 32% (275 of 865); supraclavicular disease, 16% (140 of 865); and internal mammary disease, 11% (98 of 865). All patients with involvement in the extra-axillary regional nodal basins received a radiation boost to the involved areas ≥10 Gy. Thus, over one third of patients with advanced breast cancer had their radiation plan altered by the ultrasound findings. Regional ultrasound evaluation in patients with advanced breast cancer commonly revealed abnormalities within and beyond the axilla, which changed the clinical stage of disease and the radiation treatment strategy. Therefore, regional ultrasound is beneficial in the initial staging evaluation for such patients.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22982581</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>The Value of Ultrasound in Detecting Extra-Axillary Regional Node Involvement in Patients with Advanced Breast Cancer.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Introduction. Many cancer survivors suffer from a combination of disease- and treatment-related morbidities and complaints after primary treatment. There is a growing evidence base for the effectiveness of monodimensional rehabilitation interventions; in practice, however, patients often participate in multidimensional programs. This study systematically reviews evidence regarding effectiveness of multidimensional rehabilitation programs for cancer survivors and cost-effectiveness of cancer rehabilitation in general.Methods. The published literature was systematically reviewed. Data were extracted using standardized forms and were summarized narratively.Results. Sixteen effectiveness and six cost-effectiveness studies were included. Multidimensional rehabilitation programs were found to be effective, but not more effective than monodimensional interventions, and not on all outcome measures. Effect sizes for quality of life were in the range of -0.12 (95% confidence interval [CI], -0.45-0.20) to 0.98 (95% CI, 0.69-1.29). Incremental cost-effectiveness ratios ranged from -€16,976, indicating cost savings, to €11,057 per quality-adjusted life year.Conclusions. The evidence for multidimensional interventions and the economic impact of rehabilitation studies is scarce and dominated by breast cancer studies. Studies published so far report statistically significant benefits for multidimensional interventions over usual care, most notably for the outcomes fatigue and physical functioning. An additional benefit of multidimensional over monodimensional rehabilitation was not found, but this was also sparsely reported on. Available economic evaluations assessed very different rehabilitation interventions. Yet, despite low comparability, all showed favorable cost-effectiveness ratios. Future studies should focus their designs on the comparative effectiveness and cost-effectiveness of multidimensional programs.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22982580</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Effectiveness of Multidimensional Cancer Survivor Rehabilitation and Cost-Effectiveness of Cancer Rehabilitation in General: A Systematic Review.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Hypoxia is part of the tumor microenvironment favouring cancer resistance to chemotherapy mediated by mutations in the tumor suppressor p53 gene (TP53), or by conformational wt TP53 dysfunction. Since it is important to suppress tumor adaptation to hypoxia, irrespective of p53 status, we compared the efficacy of nutlin-3 which prevents MDM2-wt p53 interactions and PRIMA-1 which promotes mutant p53 reactivation and induction of massive apoptosis, under normoxia and hypoxia, against a) SKBR3 breast carcinoma harbouring a mutant p53R175H and over-expressing erbB2; and b) genetically matched breast cancer ERα positive MCF-7 cells harbouring either wt p53 or mutant p53 R175H. Under normoxia, PRIMA-1 was active against breast cancer cells harbouring mutant p53. However, hypoxia further increased the susceptibility of mutant p53 breast cancer SKBR3 cells to lower PRIMA-1 levels, possibly through oxidative stress since this was counteracted by N-acetylcysteine. When using MCF-7 cells over-expresing mutant p53, PRIMA-1 synergized with exogenous peroxidase to increase apoptosis concomitantly with induction of PUMA and Mn-SOD, under normoxia. Wt p53 MCF-7 cells responded to hypoxia by increasing superoxide dismutase and their reactivity with the PAb240 antibody, known to recognize conformationally-inactive p53. This correlated with sensitization of wt p53 MCF-7 cells to PRIMA-1 but not to nutlin-3. PRIMA-1 toxicity against normoxic wt p53 MCF-7 cells was also decreased by Mn-SOD over-expression or when added with the glutathione antagonist, buthionine sulfoximine. This report shows for the first time that hypoxia increases PRIMA-1 toxicity in human breast cancer cells, partly by modulating p53 conformation and by inducing superoxide turnover. Our results suggest that PRIMA-1 may help to prevent hypoxia-mediated tumor chemoresistance.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22982566</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>HYPOXIA, Mn-SOD AND H(2)O(2) REGULATE p53 REACTIVATION AND PRIMA-1 TOXICITY IRRESPECTIVE OF p53 STATUS IN HUMAN BREAST CANCER CELLS.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Prodigiosin is a bacterial tripyrrole pigment with potent cytotoxicity against diverse human cancer cell lines. Endoplasmic reticulum (ER) stress is initiated by accumulation of unfolded or misfolded proteins in the ER lumen and may induce cell death when irremediable. In this study, the role of ER stress in prodigiosin-induced cytotoxicity was elucidated for the first time. Comparable to the ER stress inducer thapsigargin, prodigiosin up-regulated signature ER stress markers GRP78 and CHOP in addition to activating the IRE1, PERK and ATF6 branches of the unfolded protein response (UPR) in multiple human breast carcinoma cell lines, confirming prodigiosin as an ER stress inducer. Prodigiosin transcriptionally up-regulated CHOP, as evidenced by its promoting effect on the CHOP promoter activity. Of note, knockdown of CHOP effectively lowered prodigiosin's capacity to evoke PARP cleavage, reduce cell viability and suppress colony formation, highlighting an essential role of CHOP in prodigiosin-induced cytotoxic ER stress response. In addition, prodigiosin down-regulated BCL2 in a CHOP-dependent manner. Importantly, restoration of BCL2 expression blocked prodigiosin-induced PARP cleavage and greatly enhanced the survival of prodigiosin-treated cells, suggesting CHOP-dependent BCL2 suppression mediates prodigiosin-elicited cell death. Moreover, pharmacological inhibition of JNK by SP600125 or dominant-negative blockade of PERK-mediated eIF2 phosphorylation impaired prodigiosin-induced CHOP up-regulation and PARP cleavage. Collectively, these results identified ER stress-mediated cell death as a mode-of-action of prodigiosin's tumoricidal effect. Mechanistically, prodigiosin engages the IRE1-JNK and PERK-eIF2 branches of the UPR signaling to up-regulate CHOP, which in turn mediates BCL2 suppression to induce cell death.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22982536</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Prodigiosin activates endoplasmic reticulum stress cell death pathway in human breast carcinoma cell lines.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Lipocalin 2 (Lcn2), a member of the lipocalin family, is up-regulated in a variety of epithelial cancers. We have previously reported that Lcn2 induces the epithelial to mesenchymal transition in breast cancer through the estrogen receptor α/Slug axis and that it is a potential noninvasive biomarker of this disease. Here, we report the novel finding that Lcn2 regulates breast cancer angiogenesis. Vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF), a key angiogenic activator, was significantly increased with Lcn2 expression in MCF-7 human breast cancer cells as well as in an angiogenic line derived from MDA-MB-436 cells. Treatment with a VEGF-neutralizing antibody demonstrates that VEGF is essential for the angiogenic activity of Lcn2. We further demonstrate that Lcn2-induced VEGF is mediated through hypoxia-inducible factor 1α (HIF-1α) and that Lcn2 regulates HIF-1α through extracellular signal-regulated kinase (Erk). The regulation of HIF-1α and VEGF by Lcn2 was also demonstrated in the aggressive MDA-MB-231 cell line. Using the mouse corneal pocket assay, we found that Lcn2 significantly enhanced the angiogenesis induced by VEGF. Taken together, these results are the first to demonstrate that Lcn2 promotes angiogenesis in vitro and in vivo and suggest a novel mechanism through which Lcn2 may promote tumor progression.-Yang, J., McNeish, B., Butterfield, C., Moses, M. A. Lipocalin 2 is a novel regulator of angiogenesis in human breast cancer.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22982376</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Lipocalin 2 is a novel regulator of angiogenesis in human breast cancer.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Beta 1,4-galactosyltransferase 1 (B4GALT1) synthesizes galactose β-1,4-N-acetylglucosamine (Galβ1-4GlcNAc) groups on N-linked sugar chains of glycoproteins, which play important roles in many biological events, including the proliferation and migration of cancer cells. A previous microarray study reported that this gene is expressed by estrogen treatment in breast cancer. In this study, we examined the regulatory mechanisms and biological functions of estrogen-induced B4GALT1 expression. Our data showed that estrogen-induced expression of B4GALT1 is localized in intracellular compartments and in the plasma membrane. In addition, B4GALT1 has an enzyme activity involved in the production of the Galβ1-4GlcNAc structure. The result from a promoter assay and chromatin immunoprecipitation revealed that 3 different estrogen response elements (EREs) in the B4GALT1 promoter are critical for responsiveness to estrogen. In addition, the estrogen antagonists ICI 182,780 and ER-α-ERE binding blocker TPBM inhibit the expression of estrogen-induced B4GALT1. However, the inhibition of signal molecules relating to the extra-nuclear pathway, including the G-protein coupled receptors, Ras, and mitogen-activated protein kinases, had no inhibitory effects on B4GALT1 expression. The knock-down of the B4GALT1 gene and the inhibition of membrane B4GALT1 function resulted in the significant inhibition of estrogen-induced proliferation of MCF-7 cells. Considering these results, we propose that estrogen regulates the expression of B4GALT1 through the direct binding of ER-α to ERE and that the expressed B4GALT1 plays a crucial role in the proliferation of MCF-7 cells through its activity as a membrane receptor.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22982306</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Estrogen induced β-1,4-galactosyltransferase 1 expression regulates proliferation of human breast cancer MCF-7 cells.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>The clinical management of triple negative breast cancer (TNBC) is challenging due to the relatively aggressive biological behaviour and paucity of specific targeted therapy. A subset of TNBC patients has been reported to express androgen receptor (AR) in carcinoma cells and the manipulation of androgen signalling or AR targeted therapies have been proposed. However, the biological significance of AR in TNBC has remained relatively unknown. Therefore, this review aims to summarise the reported studies assessing the rates of AR positivity in TNBC patients and androgenic effects in TNBC cell lines. The rates of AR positivity among TNBC cases varied depending on the study population (0-53% of all TNBC patients). This difference among the reported studies may be largely due to the methodological differences of analysing AR. While the majority of cell line studies suggest that androgen increase proliferation and preliminary clinical studies suggest that AR antagonists improve the prognosis of AR positive TNBC patients, cell line transfection experiments and survival analyses of histological samples suggest that the presence of AR in tumour is either benign or predicts better survival. Therefore further translational investigations regarding the mechanisms of androgen action in TNBC are required to explain this discrepancy between clinical and basic studies.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22982153</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Androgen receptor in triple negative breast cancer.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Chronic inflammation is involved in initiation as well as progression of cancer. Semapimod, a tetravalent guanylhydrazon and formerly known as CNI-1493, inhibits the release of inflammatory cytokines from activated macrophages and this effect is partly mediated by the vagus nerve. Our previously findings demonstrated that inactivation of vagus nerve activity as well sensory neurons enhanced visceral metastasis of 4THM breast carcinoma. Hence semapimod by activating vagus nerve may inhibit breast cancer metastasis. Here, effects of semapimod on breast cancer metastasis, the role of vagal sensory neurons on this effect and changes in mediators of the neuroimmune connection, such as Substance P (SP) as well as neprilysin-like activity, were examined. Vagotomy was performed on half of the control animals that were treated with Semapimod following orthotopic injection of 4THM breast carcinoma cells. Semapimod decreased lung and liver metastasis in control but not in vagotomized animals with an associated increased SP levels in sensory nerve endings. Semapimod also increased neprilysin-like activity in lung tissue of control animals but not in tumor-bearing animals. This is the first report demonstrating that semapimod enhances vagal sensory nerve activity and may have anti-tumoral effects under in-vivo conditions. Further studies, however are required to elucidate the conditions and the mechanisms involved in anti-tumoral effects of semapimod.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22982142</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Activation of vagus nerve by Semapimod alters Substance P levels and decreases breast cancer metastasis.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>A series of new 1,3-disubstituted-1H-naphtho[1,2-e][1,3]oxazines (3 and 7) was synthesized in good yields and the structure was determined with the help of NMR, 2D-NMR, HRMS studies and X-ray crystallography. These compounds were tested in vitro for their antibacterial activity against Gram-positive and Gram-negative bacteria and as well as for antifungal activity. The compounds 3c, 3e, 7a, 7d and 7k showed significant antibacterial activity and 7l showed moderate antifungal activity. The cytotoxicity of 1,3-disubstituted-1H-naphtho[1,2-e][1,3]oxazines showed that 3e and 7e are more effective against breast, lung and colon cell proliferation.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22982123</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Synthesis, antimicrobial and cytotoxicity study of 1,3-disubstituted-1H-naphtho[1,2-e][1,3]oxazines.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Emodin is a poorly bioavailable but promising plant-derived anticancer drug candidate. The low oral bioavailability of emodin is due to its extensive glucuronidation in the intestine and liver. Caco-2 cell culture model was used to investigate the interplay between UDP-glucuronosyltransferases (UGTs) and efflux transporters in the intestinal disposition of emodin. Bidirectional transport assays of emodin at different concentrations were performed in the Caco-2 monolayers with or without multidrug resistance-associated protein (MRP) and breast cancer resistance protein (BCRP) efflux transporter chemical inhibitors. The bidirectional permeability of emodin and its glucuronide in the Caco-2 monolayers was determined. Emodin was rapidly metabolized to emodin glucuronide in Caco-2 cells. LTC4, a potent inhibitor of MRP2, decreased the efflux of emodin glucuronide and also substantially increased the intracellular glucuronide level in the basolateral-to-apical (B-A) direction. MK-571, chemical inhibitor of MRP2, MRP3, and MRP4, significantly reduced the efflux of glucuronide in the apical-to-basolateral (A-B) and B-A directions in a dose-dependent manner. However, dipyridamole, a BCRP chemical inhibitor demonstrated no effect on formation and efflux of emodin glucuronide in Caco-2 cells. In conclusion, UGT is a main metabolic pathway for emodin in the intestine, and the MRP family is composed of major efflux transporters responsible for the excretion of emodin glucuronide in the intestine. The coupling of UGTs and MRP efflux transporters causes the extensive metabolism, excretion, and low bioavailability of emodin.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22982073</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Coupling of UDP-glucuronosyltransferases and multidrug resistance-associated proteins is responsible for the intestinal disposition and poor bioavailability of emodin.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Neurokinin 1 (NK1) encodes full-length (NK1-FL) and truncated (NK1-Tr) receptors, with distinct 3' UTR. NK1-Tr exerts oncogenic functions and is increased in breast cancer (BC). Enhanced transcription of NK1 resulted in higher level of NK1-Tr. The 3' UTR of these two transcripts are distinct with NK1-Tr terminating at a premature stop codon. NK1-Tr mRNA gained an advantage over NK1-FL with regards to translation. This is due to the ability of miR519B to interact with sequences within the 3' UTR of NK1-FL, but not NK1-Tr since the corresponding region is omitted. MiR519b suppressed the translation of NK1-FL in T47D and MDA-MB-231 resulting increased NK1-Tr protein. Cytokines can induce the transcription of NK1. However, our studies indicated that translation appeared to be independent of cytokine production by the BC cells (BCCs). This suggested that transcription and translation of NK1 might be independent. The findings were validated in vivo. MiR-519b suppressed the growth of MDA-MB-231 in 7/10 nude BALB/c. In total, increased NK1-Tr in BCCs is due to enhanced transcription and suppressed translation of NK1-FL by miR-519b to reduced tumor growth. In summary, we report on miRNA as a method to further regulate the expression of a spiced variant to promote oncogenesis. In addition, the findings have implications for therapy with NK1 antagonists. The oncogenic effect of NK1-Tr must be considered to improve the efficacy of current drugs to NK1.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22981979</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>An indirect role for the oncomir-519b in the expression of truncated neurokinin-1 in breast cancer cells.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string></string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22981974</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>[Breast cancers and gene expression signatures: Here and now.]</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Bisphenol A is widely used in polymer products in food and beverage containers, baby bottles, dental sealants and fillings, adhesives, protective coatings, flame retardants, water supply pipes, and compact discs, and is found in the environment and in placental tissue, fetuses and breast milk. We have recently reported that a single neonatal exposure to bisphenol A can induce persistent aberrations in spontaneous behavior, in a dose-dependent manner, and affect the adult response to the cholinergic agent nicotine. Furthermore, other recent reports indicate that pre- and perinatal exposure to bisphenol A can induce neurotoxic effects. The present study indicates that a single neonatal exposure to bisphenol A, on postnatal day 10, during the peak of the brain growth spurt, can alter the adult levels of proteins important for normal brain development (CaMKII and synaptophysin). These alterations are induced in both male and female mice and effects are seen in both hippocampus and cerebral cortex. These results further support our recent study showing that neonatal exposure to bisphenol A can act as a developmental neurotoxicant and the effects are similar to effects seen after a single postnatal exposure to other POPs, such as PBDEs, PCBs and PFCs.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22981971</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>A single exposure to Bisphenol A alters the levels of important neuroproteins in adult male and female mice.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string></string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22981939</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>A Mother and Daughter With Phyllodes Tumors of the Breast.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string></string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22981938</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>A Patient With Metastatic Breast Cancer 15 Years After Bilateral Prophylactic Total Mastectomy and Oophorectomy.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>OBJECTIVE: The objective of this study was to assess the value of research of the RxPONDER study, an ongoing comparative effectiveness RCT designed to evaluate a 21-gene profile in early stage, node-positive breast cancer. METHODS: We developed a disease-based decision-analytic model to compare use of the 21-gene profile versus standard care. Key clinical data were derived from SWOG-8814, an RCT of chemotherapy in lymph node-positive breast cancer. Other model parameters were obtained from published sources. Probabilistic simulations and value of information calculations were used to assess the expected value of sample information (EVSI) and the expected value of sample parameter information (EVSPI). RESULTS: The cost of the RxPONDER trial is expected to be at least $27million. The expected value of research of the RxPONDER trial ranged from $450million to $1billion, representing a return of 17 to 39 times the projected cost of the trial. The primary objective of RxPONDER, to assess survival, had the largest estimated value relative to other model inputs. The value of RxPONDER increased by $50million to $100million after stakeholder input on additional data collection. CONCLUSION: The RxPONDER study appears to represent a good investment of public research funds. Stakeholder engagement and assessment of the return on investment should be considered to optimize and quantify the value of comparative effectiveness studies.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22981891</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>The value of comparative effectiveness research: Projected return on investment of the RxPONDER trial (SWOG S1007).</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Publicly organized population breast cancer screening is presently hotly debated. Indeed, population screening is poorly effective, induces harms in a healthy population and is costly. However, stopping all kind of screening of low- and average-risk women would be problematic as about 70% of breast cancers are diagnosed in those subgroups, and maintaining current population screening in high-risk women would be insufficient. We propose herein a review about the advantages and the inconvenients of individualized screening. The latter could be a more efficient strategy. The principles of individualized screening are (a) to start from the age at which the breast cancer risk is equal to that for an average women aged 50 years, (b) to stop when the risk of co-mortality exceeds the risk of breast cancer mortality, (c) to adapt the exams frequency and the imaging modalities to the individual risk and to the breast density, (d) to reassess regularly and individually the screening strategy, and (e) to discuss honestly with each woman in order to help her to decide if she participates or not.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22981888</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Should we individualize breast cancer screening?</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Caspases (CASPs), play a crucial role in the development and progression of cancer. We evaluated the association between two polymorphisms (rs4645978 and rs4645981) of the CASP9 gene and the risk of breast cancer (BC). Genotypes and allelic frequencies for the two polymorphisms were determined in 261 patients with breast cancer and 480 healthy controls. Polymerase chain reaction-restriction fragment length polymorphisms were used, and statistical significance was determined by the χ(2) test. Carriers of the rs4645978G allele (AG and GG genotypes) were at higher risk for BC than individuals with other genotypes (odds ratio (OR) 1.59, 95% confidence interval (CI) 1.07-2.37, P = 0.022). The rs4645978GG genotype, in particular, was associated with the highest risk for BC development (OR 2.25, 95% CI 1.45-3.49, P = 0.0003). Similarly, individuals with at least one rs4645981T allele were at a significantly increased risk of developing BC compared with those harboring the CC genotype (OR 2.75, 95% CI 1.99-3.78, P < 0.0001), and the risk of BC increased with increasing numbers of rs4645981T alleles (OR 2.66, 95% CI 1.91-3.69, P < 0.0001 for the CT genotype; OR 3.95, 95% CI 1.58-9.88, P = 0.004 for the TT genotype). The CASP9 promoter polymorphisms rs4645978 and rs4645981 are associated with BC susceptibility and suggest that CASP9 transcriptional regulation is an important factor during BC development.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22981751</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Caspase 9 promoter polymorphisms confer increased susceptibility to breast cancer.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string></string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22981750</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>A comparison of three methods for non-palpable breast cancer excision.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>INTRODUCTION: A new approach for implant based breast reconstruction (IBBR) is the use of a titanium-coated polypropylene mesh (TCPM) as an alternative to acellular dermal matrix (ADM). This TCPM has a good biocompatibility and can be used similarly to ADM. The aim of this study is to discuss indications, limitations and complications of TCPM in IBBR. METHODS: A retrospective analysis of 42 patients undergoing immediate or delayed IBBR using a TCPM was performed. Primary endpoints were incidence of infection and expander/implant with mesh removal due to infected fluid collection or extrusion. RESULTS: In two patients, mild hematoma, seroma or infection occurred. Skin necrosis or capsular contraction was observed in one patient. Mesh explantation was needed in 3 cases. These events were higher among the first cases and in patients with postoperative skin infection (p = 0.003). CONCLUSION: In selected patients with adequate soft tissue cover TCPM seems to be a helpful tool for implant stabilization in terms of lateral stabilization and fixation of the musculus pectoralis major. In comparison to ADM, TCPM is cheaper and initial results are promising, but further follow-up data are necessary. In patients with poor soft tissue cover ADM should be used.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22981749</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>A short-term follow-up of implant based breast reconstruction using a titanium-coated polypropylene mesh (TiLoop(®) Bra).</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>BACKGROUND: Breast cancer is the most commonly diagnosed cancer in women worldwide and characterized its by molecular and clinical heterogeneity. Gene expression profiling studies have classified breast cancers into five subtypes: luminal A, luminal B, HER-2 overexpressing, basal-like, and normal breast-like. Although clinical differences between subtypes have been well described in the literature, etiologic heterogeneity have not been fully studied. The aim of this study was to assess the associations between several hormonal and nonhormonal risk factors and molecular subtypes of breast cancer. METHODS: This cross-sectional study consisted of 1884 invasive breast cancer cases. Variables studied included family history, age at first full-term pregnancy, number of children, duration of lactation, menstruation history, menopausal status, blood type, smoking, obesity, oral contraceptive use, hormone replacement therapy and in vitro fertilization. The odds ratios (OR) and 95% confidence intervals (CI) were estimated using multivariate logistic regression analysis. RESULTS: Thousand two-hundred and forty nine patients had luminal A, 234 had luminal B, 169 had HER-2 overexpressing and 232 had triple negative breast cancer. The age of ≥40 years was found to be a risk factor for luminal A (OR 1.41 95% CI 1.15-1.74; p=0.001) and HER-2 overexpressing subtype (OR: 1.51, 95% CI: 1.01-2.25; p=0.04). Women who were nulliparous (OR 1.48, 95% CI 1.03-2.13; p=0.03) or who had their first full-term pregnancy at age 30 years or older (OR 1.25 95% CI 0.83-1.88; p=0.04) were at increased risk of luminal breast cancer, whereas women with more than two children had a decreased risk (OR 0.68, 95% CI 0.47-0.97; p=0.03). Breast-feeding was also a protective factor for luminal subtype (OR 0.74, 95% CI 0.53-1.04; p=0.04) when compared to non-luminal breast cancer. We found increased risks for postmenopausal women with HER-2 overexpressing (OR 2.20, 95% CI 0.93-5.17; p=0.04) and luminal A (OR 1.87, 95% CI 0.93-3.90, p=0.02) breast cancers, who used hormone replacement therapy for 5 years or more. Overweight and obesity significantly increased the risk of triple negative subtype (OR 1.89 95% CI 1.06-3.37; p=0.04 and OR 1.90 95% CI 1.00-3.61; p=0.03), on the contrary, decreased the risk of luminal breast cancer (OR 0.63 95% CI 0.43-0.95; p=0.02 and OR 0.50 95% CI 0.32-0.76; p=0.002, respectively) in premenopausal women. There were no significant differences between risk of breast cancer subtypes and early menarche, late menopause, family history, postmenopausal obesity, oral contraseptive use, smoking, in vitro fertilization, blood groups and use of hands. CONCLUSIONS: Reproductive and hormonal characteristics (breastfeeding, parity, age at first full-term birth, hormone replacement therapy) were associated with luminal subtype, compared to non-luminal breast cancer, as consistent with previous studies. Obesity and overweight increased the risk of triple negative subtype, particularly in premenopausal women. Older age and use of hormone replacement therapy were related to the risk of HER-2 overexpressing breast cancer. Our data suggest a significant heterogeneity in association of traditional breast cancer risk factors and tumor subtypes.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22981738</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Association between common risk factors and molecular subtypes in breast cancer patients.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Basement membrane (BM) is a complex network of interacting proteins, including type IV collagen (Col IV) that acts as a scaffold that stabilizes the physical structures of tissues and regulates cellular processes. In the mammary gland, BM is a continuous deposit that separates epithelial cells from stroma, and its degradation is related with an increased potential for invasion and metastasis. Epithelial to mesenchymal transition (EMT) is a process by which epithelial cells are transdifferentiated to one mesenchymal state, and is a normal process during embryonic development, tissue remodeling and wound healing, as well as it has been implicated during cancer progression. In breast cancer cells, native Col V induces migration and gelatinases secretion. However, the role of native Col IV on the EMT process in human mammary epithelial cells remains to be investigated. In the present study, we demonstrate that native Col IV induces down-regulation of E-cadherin expression, accompanied with an increase of Snail1, Snail2 and Sip1 transcripts. Native Col IV also induces an increase in N-cadherin and vimentin expression, an increase of MMP-2 secretion, the activation of FAK and NFκB, cell migration and invasion in MCF10A cells. In summary, these findings demonstrate, for the first time, that native Col IV induces an EMT-like process in MCF10A human mammary non-tumorigenic epithelial cells.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22981734</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Native type IV collagen induces an epithelial to mesenchymal transition-like process in mammary epithelial cells MCF10A.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>PURPOSE: Intraoperative radiation therapy (IORT) with low-energy x-rays is used to treat the tumor bed during breast-conserving surgery. The purpose was to determine the relative biologic effectiveness (RBE) of 50-kV x-rays for inactivation of cells irradiated in a tumor-bed phantom. METHODS AND MATERIALS: The RBE was determined for clonogenic inactivation of human tumor and normal cells (MCF7, human umbilical vein endothelial cells, normal skin fibroblasts), and hamster V79 cells. The 50-kV x-rays from the Intrabeam machine (Carl Zeiss Surgical) with a spherical 4-cm applicator were used. Cells were irradiated in a water-equivalent phantom at defined distances (8.1-22.9 mm) from the applicator surface. The 50-kV x-rays from a surface therapy machine (Dermopan, Siemens) were included for comparison; 6-MV x-rays were used as reference radiation. RESULTS: At 8.1-mm depth in the phantom (dose rate 15.1 Gy/h), mean RBE values of 50-kV x-rays from Intrabeam were 1.26 to 1.42 for the 4 cell types at doses yielding surviving fractions in the range of 0.01 to 0.5. Confidence intervals were in the range of 1.2 and 1.5. Similar RBE values were found for 50-kV x-rays from Dermopan for V79 (1.30, CI 1.25-1.36, P=.74) and GS4 (1.42, CI 1.30-1.54, P=.67). No significant dependence of RBE on dose was found for Intrabeam, but RBE decreased at a larger distance (12.7 mm; 9.8 Gy/h). CONCLUSIONS: An increased clinically relevant RBE was found for cell irradiation with Intrabeam at depths in the tumor bed targeted by IORT. The reduced RBE values at larger distances may be related to increased repair of sublethal damage during protracted irradiation or to hardening of the photon beam energy.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22981707</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Relative Biologic Effectiveness (RBE) of 50 kV X-rays Measured in a Phantom for Intraoperative Tumor-Bed Irradiation.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>BACKGROUND: Most personalized cancer care strategies involving DNA sequencing are highly reliant on acquiring sufficient fresh or frozen tissue. It has been challenging to comprehensively evaluate the genome of advanced prostate cancer (PCa) because of limited access to metastatic tissue. OBJECTIVE: To demonstrate the feasibility of a novel next-generation sequencing (NGS)-based platform that can be used with archival formalin-fixed paraffin-embedded (FFPE) biopsy tissue to evaluate the spectrum of DNA alterations seen in advanced PCa. DESIGN, SETTING, AND PARTICIPANTS: FFPE samples (including archival prostatectomies and prostate needle biopsies) were obtained from 45 patients representing the spectrum of disease: localized PCa, metastatic hormone-naive PCa, and metastatic castration-resistant PCa (CRPC). We also assessed paired primaries and metastases to understand disease heterogeneity and disease progression. INTERVENTION: At least 50 ng of tumor DNA was extracted from FFPE samples and used for hybridization capture and NGS using the Illumina HiSeq 2000 platform. OUTCOME MEASUREMENTS AND STATISTICAL ANALYSIS: A total of 3320 exons of 182 cancer-associated genes and 37 introns of 14 commonly rearranged genes were evaluated for genomic alterations. RESULTS AND LIMITATIONS: We obtained an average sequencing depth of >900X. Overall, 44% of CRPCs harbored genomic alterations involving the androgen receptor gene (AR), including AR copy number gain (24% of CRPCs) or AR point mutation (20% of CRPCs). Other recurrent mutations included transmembrane protease, serine 2 gene (TMPRSS2):v-ets erythroblastosis virus E26 oncogene homolog (avian) gene (ERG) fusion (44%); phosphatase and tensin homolog gene (PTEN) loss (44%); tumor protein p53 gene (TP53) mutation (40%); retinoblastoma gene (RB) loss (28%); v-myc myelocytomatosis viral oncogene homolog (avian) gene (MYC) gain (12%); and phosphatidylinositol-4,5-bisphosphate 3-kinase, catalytic subunit α gene (PIK3CA) mutation (4%). There was a high incidence of genomic alterations involving key genes important for DNA repair, including breast cancer 2, early onset gene (BRCA2) loss (12%) and ataxia telangiectasia mutated gene (ATM) mutations (8%); these alterations are potentially targetable with poly(adenosine diphosphate-ribose)polymerase inhibitors. A novel and actionable rearrangement involving the v-raf murine sarcoma viral oncogene homolog B1 gene (BRAF) was also detected. CONCLUSIONS: This first-in-principle study demonstrates the feasibility of performing in-depth DNA analyses using FFPE tissue and brings new insight toward understanding the genomic landscape within advanced PCa.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22981675</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Targeted Next-generation Sequencing of Advanced Prostate Cancer Identifies Potential Therapeutic Targets and Disease Heterogeneity.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>RATIONALE AND OBJECTIVES: Quantitatively analyze the computed tomography (CT) attenuation effects caused by bismuth shields, which are used to reduce superficial organ dose. MATERIALS AND METHODS: The solid water uniformity section of the American College of Radiology CT phantom was scanned with a modified chest CT protocol. Scans were performed with a bismuth breast shield in multiple configurations, emphasizing three clinically relevant orientations. Attenuation effects were measured as changes in mean Hounsfield unit (HU) values of equal midsagittal regions of interest (ROI). Multiple statistical techniques were used in regression analysis. RESULTS: Bismuth shielding resulted in significant positive shifts of the expected Hounsfield unit values. The mean nonshielded CT attenuation was -0.16 ± 0.75 HU. Based on the clinically relevant ROI distance from the shield (∼3-16 cm), the shielded values ranged from 43.8-4 HU, 45.8-10.1 HU, and 50.6-4.5 HU for shields 1, 2, and 3, respectively. All shield configurations displayed a statistically significant shift (P < .0001) at all distance ranges. The best fitting regression model was a quadratic function of distance versus logarithmic function of HU. A prediction table of the approximate shift in water HU values as a function of ROI distance from the shield was generated per shield type from their respective close-fitting regressions. CONCLUSIONS: The data support the claim that bismuth shields increase the attenuation of water, which can cause inaccurate characterization of simple fluid, giving the appearance of complex fluid or even solid density. However, there is potential for anticipation of the attenuation effects to validate continued use of these shields for dose reduction.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22981602</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Shielding Artificially Increases the Attenuation of Water: Study of CT Gradient Attenuation Induced by Shielding (CT GAINS).</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>During self-renewal of the hematopoietic stem cells there is a potential for these new cells to develop into abnormal malignant cells due to environmental, chemical or microbial challenges. This may lead to blood malignancies, including leukemia and lymphoma. Our laboratory was the first to develop a mouse model to study the development of lymphoma among pups of retrovirus infected mothers. We have established that if the newborn pups suckle breast milk from the mothers infected with a temperature sensitive Moloney Murine Leukemia Virus (MoMuLV-ts1), they develop lymphoma. Stem and progenitor cell populations were determined from blood, spleen, and thymus samples in infected mice with and without lymphoma using flow cytometry and specific protein markers, including CD117+/CD34+; CD117+/Sca-1+; CD135+/Sca-1+; Ter119+/CD71+ and CD117+/CD45+. Some stem cell populations were increased in infected mice with lymphoma. These stem cells appear to be involved in the development of lymphoma in our mouse model.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22981528</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Hematopoietic stem and progenitor cell populations in MoMuLV-ts-1 induced lymphoma in a murine model.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>BACKGROUND: The deep inferior epigastric artery perforator (DIEP) flap is currently one of the preferred methods of autologous breast reconstruction. As a microsurgical flap, it is subjected to ischaemia-reperfusion injury and no reflow phenomenon, both of which are influenced by prolonged ischaemia times. In this work, we review the rates of microvascular complications according to ischaemia times in patients submitted to DIEP flap breast reconstruction. METHODS: A retrospective review of 182 patients submitted to breast reconstruction with DIEP flap was conducted. Patients were first classified according to ischaemia time percentiles 25, 50, 75 and 100 comparing the rates of microvascular complications using Fisher's exact test. Next, patients were separated in two groups above and below P(50). Using Student's t-test and Fisher's exact test, univariate analysis was conducted to compare all demographic and surgical variables as well as complications between these groups. Finally, multivariate analysis using binary logistic regression was performed to determine whether or not ischaemia time was an independent risk factor for microvascular complications. RESULTS: Flap success rate was 97%. Eighteen flaps (9.5%) presented some form of microvascular event. Higher rates of complications were observed as ischaemia time increased (p < 0.05). On multivariate analysis, ischaemia time was found to be an independent risk factor for microvascular complications (odds ratio (OR) 3.81, p = 0.03). Flaps with ischaemia longer than 1.5-2 h were observed to be at higher risk of developing some form of vascular compromise. CONCLUSIONS: Ischaemia time is an independent risk factor for microvascular complications in the DIEP flap for breast reconstruction. Keeping such time to the minimum necessary and avoiding needless delays is likely to improve flap survival.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22981497</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Increments in ischaemia time induces microvascular complications in the DIEP flap for breast reconstruction.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Omega-3 fatty acid deprivation during development reduces performance in learning tasks, and dietary DHA supplementation improves learning ability and enhances long term memory in both young and old animals. However, little attention has been paid to the effect of maternal intake of Omega-3 fatty acids on hippocampal function in their pups. Randomly some of the pregnant dams were supplemented with Omega-3 essential fatty acid, others with tap-water, during pregnancy and breast-feeding by gavage daily. Spatial learning and memory was tested in Morris water maze. Field potentials from the dentate gyrus were recorded in response to medial perforant pathway in urethane-anesthetized pups. Omega-3-treated rats found the platform less traveled and closer to platform than control animals. However the pups from both groups show the same performance in retrieval task. No differences were found between corresponding animal groups in the input-output curves of the field potential slopes, suggesting no effect of Omega-3 supplementation on basal synaptic efficacy. Potentiation of population spike amplitude was much higher in pups of Omega-3 treated dams than control. Up to now Omega 3 fatty acid has been shown to be beneficial on the synaptic plasticity only under some pathological conditions. For the first time, we showed improved dentate gyrus-LTP and enhanced Morris water maze performance in healthy pups from healthy dams treated with Omega-3 fatty acids during pregnancy and breast-feeding period. Molecular studies are needed to explain Omega-3 effect on hippocampal synaptic plasticity.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22981414</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Maternal intake of Omega-3 essential fatty acids improves long term potentiation in the dentate gyrus and Morris water maze performance in rats.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>BACKGROUND: While the arterial perfusion of the anterior abdominal wall has been extensively described in the literature, little has been published on the venous drainage of the deep inferior epigastric flap (DIEP). The present study was performed to further clarify the venous drainage of DIEP flap, which remains a common vascular complication of this flap. METHODS: We assessed the efficiency of venous outflow on 19 patients undergoing DIEP flap breast reconstruction, determining relative haemoglobin concentration (rHB) as an indicator of venous congestion. After the flap had been isolated on the perforator vessels, a selective clamping and declamping of the single lateral and medial perforator was performed and several measurements were carried out using a micro-lightguide spectrophotometer device (O2C: Oxygen to See; LEA Medizintechnik, Gießen, Germany). In addition, the efficacy of venous supercharging with ipsilateral and contralateral superficial inferior epigastric veins (SIEVs) was quantified. RESULTS: For the sake of simplicity, we applied the classic perfusion zones of the lower abdomen as suggested by Hartrampf (1983). Regardless of lateral or medial DIEP perforator veins, zone IV showed the least venous outflow, while we observed the highest drainage in zone I. There was no significant difference between the venous drainage of the two immediately adjacent zones II and III. Supercharging with the contralateral SIEV showed a significantly better venous drainage in the contralateral zones II and IV, whereas the ipsilateral SIEV did not present any significant improvement in the venous drainage of any zone. CONCLUSION: This study evaluated the characteristics of the venous outflow of the DIEP flap, based on the single perforator and the SIEVs. Our findings revealed that zones II and III have a similar venous drainage regardless of the perforator veins used. The supercharging of the contralateral SIEV leads to an improved venous outflow compared to the ipsilateral SIEV. This may support surgeons in minimising venous complications and may improve the degree of DIEP flap survival.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22981386</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>A quantitative analysis of the venous outflow of the deep inferior epigastric flap (DIEP) based on the perforator veins and the efficiency of superficial inferior epigastric vein (SIEV) supercharging.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Multiple lines of evidence support an inverse association between consumption of garlic and the risk of cancer. Chemopreventive effects of garlic have been attributed to its oil-soluble sulfur ingredients, such as diallyl sulfide (DAS), diallyl disulfide (DADS), and diallyl trisulfide (DATS), but their underlying molecular mechanisms remain largely unresolved. In the present study, we found that DATS showed most potent anti-proliferative effects in human breast cancer MCF-7 cells. MCF-7 cells treated with DATS underwent apoptotic death as revealed by a progressive increase in the proportion of the sub-G0/G1 cell population and a typical pattern of annexin V/propidium iodide staining. DATS induced phosphorylation of the antiapoptotic Bcl-2 and proteolytic cleavage of poly(ADP-ribose)polymerase (PARP) in MCF-7 cells. DATS treatment activated c-Jun N-terminal kinase (JNK). DATS-induced apoptosis was blunted in MCF-7 cells treated with a specific JNK inhibitor SP600125 or transiently transfected with dominant negative JNK. DATS treatment resulted in accumulation of reactive oxygen spices (ROS). DATS-induced apoptosis as well as activation of JNK was abrogated by N-acetyl-l-cysteine (NAC). Furthermore, DATS induced phosphorylation and expression of c-Jun, which were attenuated by NAC. MCF-7 cells treated with DATS also exhibited increased DNA binding activity of AP-1, which was blocked by NAC and the JNK inhibitor. Proteolytic cleavage of PARP induced by DATS was abrogated in the cells transfected with c-jun siRNA. Oral administration of 5μmol/kg DATS to female Balb/c mice inhibited the growth of human MCF-7 cell tumor xenografts. These results suggest that DATS-induced apoptosis is mediated through ROS generation and subsequent activation of JNK and AP-1.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22981381</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Diallyl trisulfide induces apoptosis in human breast cancer cells through ROS-mediated activation of JNK and AP-1.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>OBJECTIVE: to gain a deeper understanding of the experiences of childbearing in women with intellectual disabililty (ID). DESIGN/SETTING: ten women with ID, who had given birth within seven years, were interviewed twice and data were analysed with content analysis. FINDINGS: the overarching theme was: Struggling for motherhood with an ID. The significance of having an intellectual disability became evident when the women encountered mixed reactions from partners and relatives, who sometimes suggested an induced abortion. The women disclosed their diagnosis if they believed it was beneficial for them. Throughout the process the women also felt anxious and distressed about the custody of the child. Women experienced the pregnancy as a physical and psychological transition. It was mostly a happy and responsible life event, and the women were aware of physical signs in their bodies and contact with the unborn child. Parent education was considered important but not adequately adapted to their needs. The women described the delivery as hard and painful work, sometimes difficult to understand and they had different strategies to handle the pain and strain of labour. The child was welcomed with warmth and curiosity by the women, who cared for and breast fed the child even if the hospital environment could be confusing and continued custody not taken for granted. CONCLUSIONS: women with ID struggle for motherhood and fear losing custody of the child. Professionals need to identify and support these women, who may not always disclose their diagnosis. Since pregnancy, delivery and the transition into motherhood can be difficult to understand, information and support should be better tailored to their needs.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22981380</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Struggling for motherhood with an intellectual disability-A qualitative study of women's experiences in Sweden.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>OBJECTIVE: The objective of the study was to assess the infertility patient knowledge of reproductive outcomes affected by obesity. STUDY DESIGN: This was a prospective survey study of 150 female infertility patients in an academic medical center. Subjects were administered the Rapid Estimate of Adult Literacy in Medicine-Short Form and a questionnaire on the health risks of obesity, and investigators obtained height and weight measurements. RESULTS: Subjects' age ranged from 21 to 45 years (mean 34.8 ± 4.94 SD) and body mass index ranged from 17.9 to 62.9 kg/m(2) (mean 26.5 ± 7.54 SD). The following percentages of women were aware that obesity increases the risk of infertility (82.7%), irregular periods (70.0%), miscarriage (60.7%), cesarean section (48.7%), breast cancer (38.7%), birth defects (29.3%), stillbirth (22.7%), and endometrial cancer (20.7%). CONCLUSION: Among women with infertility, there is limited knowledge of reproductive outcomes affected by obesity. Public education is needed to increase awareness. Women undergoing fertility treatment are motivated for reproductive success and may be uniquely receptive to obesity education and weight loss intervention.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22981319</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Infertility patients' knowledge of the effects of obesity on reproductive health outcomes.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>In the last decades several studies tested the hypothesis that at early development stages certain foods or nutrients, in specific amounts, fed during limited sensitive periods, may determine an endocrine metabolic asset leading to clinical alterations that take place decades later (early nutritional programming of long term health). Evidence is mounting for programming effects of infant feeding. Observational studies indicate that breast feeding, relative to formula feeding, reduces the risk for obesity at school age by about 20% even after adjustment for biological and sociodemographic confounders. Moreover, breastfeeding is constantly associated with increased neurodevelopmental scores up to early adulthood, while its outcome in terms of delayed decay of brain function is still unknown. Besides the environment surrounding breastfeeding, specific nutrients within human milk may play a direct role. With the introduction of solids the major changes in diet are represented by the sudden decrease of fat intake from 50 to 30% of total energy. A protein excess, commonly found throughout all European Countries, has been associated to a higher risk of adiposity in early childhood, as confirmed by first reports from a large European trial. The amount of fat does not seem to be associated with later adiposity, while its quality may affect blood lipoproteins, blood pressure and neurodevelopmental performance. Early intake of dietary fibers might also have beneficial effects. Epidemiologic data show that episodes of rapid growth (growth acceleration hypothesis), whichever the dietary habits, are associated with later unfavorable health conditions and should be prevented.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22981292</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Early nutrition patterns and diseases of adulthood: A plausible link?</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Idiopathic granulomatous mastitis (IGM) is a rare localized granulomatosis of unknown aetiology that usually affects women of childbearing age. It often mimics breast carcinoma or abscess. Histopathologic evaluation and elimination of the others aetiologies of granuloma play a crucial role in the diagnosis. Its etiopathogeny remains poorly understood, but Corynebacteria might be involved. The disease course is usually protracted, with a significant impact on quality of life. The management of IGM remains controversial, but corticosteroids are usually the first-line treatment.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22981187</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>[Idiopathic granulomatous mastitis.]</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>It is known that interleukin-18 (IL-18) is a proinflammatory cytokine with dual effects on tumor development and progression. It can increase the immune defense against tumor cells. Polymorphisms in the IL-18 genes are known to influence both expression levels and may be associated with outcome of cancers. This study was aimed to find out the possible association of IL-18 polymorphism at position -607 C/A (rs1946518) with breast cancer in a sample of Iranian population. We investigated IL-18 rs1946518 polymorphism on 72 breast cancer patients and 93 cancer free women. Genotyping was done using amplification refractory mutation system-PCR (ARMS-PCR). We found no significant differences between breast cancer patients and control subjects regarding IL-18 rs1946518 polymorphism (χ2=1.78, p=0.411). In conclusion, our finding showed that IL-18 rs1946518 polymorphism was not associated with breast cancer in a sample of Iranian population.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22980562</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Association of -607 C/A Polymorphism of IL-18 Gene (rs1946518) with Breast Cancer Risk in Zahedan, Southeast Iran.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Fibroadenomas are the most common benign breast lesion in female adolescents. However, it is important to recognize that a small percentage have been shown to progress to giant fibroadenomas. Giant fibroadenomas can spontaneously infarct leading to significant morbidity and are also difficult to distinguish from the more aggressive phyllodes tumors.We describe the first case, to the best of our knowledge, of a 12-year-old girl who presented with a giant fibroadenoma complicated by a central infarct and an intra-lesional hemorrhage from a trauma to the breast.The complicated giant fibroadenoma with an intra-lesional hemorrhage has characteristics of both benign and malignant lesions, and is difficult to distinguish by history and physical alone. Ultrasonography is a valuable tool yet the core needle biopsy remains the gold standard to confirm the diagnosis.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22980414</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>An atypical growth of a giant fibroadenoma after trauma.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string></string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22980278</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Sweat gland carcinoma versus metastatic breast carcinoma: A continued struggle among clinicians and dermatopathologists.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string></string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22980163</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Clinical Pearls in Breast Disease.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Although significant consideration has been devoted to women participation in breast cancer prevention programs, our understanding about the psychosocial factors which influence participation remains incomplete.The study applied a quantitative approach based on the cross-sectional survey design and multistage cluster random sampling. A total of 400 women aged 35-69 years, were surveyed at 4 obstetric and gynecologic clinics affiliated to Tehran University of Medical Sciences in Tehran: the participation levels of 86 women who have had a mammogram were analyzed based on their self-efficacy, belief, social influence, and barriers concerning mammography utilization.Consistent with the study framework, in bivariate analysis, the higher level of women's participation in breast cancer prevention programs was significantly related to more positive belief about mammography (p&lt; .05), greater social influence on mammography (p&lt; .01) and fewer barriers to mammography (p&lt; .01). Self efficacy (p= .114) was not significantly related to the higher level of participation.RESULTS suggest that women's participation levels in breast cancer prevention programs might be associated with the specific psychosocial factors on breast cancer preventive behavior such as mammography screening.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22980116</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>The Influence of Psycho-social Factors on Participation Levels in Community-based Breast Cancer Prevention Programs in Tehran, Iran.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>The prevalence of chemotherapy-related cardiac disease is increasing and management demands a multidisciplinary approach from cardiologists and oncologists. Pretreatment identification of predisposing risk factors and assessment of cardiac function before and at intervals during and after therapy with cardiotoxic agents are necessary. In clinical practice, surveillance is largely performed using transthoracic echocardiography or multi-gated radionuclide angiography. Imaging strategies that detect cardiac injury before overt left ventricular systolic dysfunction provide an opportunity for early intervention and improved cardiac outcomes.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22980061</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Breast cancer therapies and cardiomyopathy.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>High-frequency (20-80 MHz) ultrasonic measurements have the potential to detect cancer and other pathologies within breast tissues in real time, and thus may assist surgeons in obtaining negative or cancer free margins during lumpectomy. To study this approach, ultrasonic tests were performed on 34 lumpectomy margins and other breast tissue specimens from 17 patients to provide pulse-echo and through-transmission waveforms. Time-domain waveform analysis yielded ultrasonic attenuation, while fast Fourier transforms of the waveforms produced first- and second-order ultrasonic spectra. A multivariate analysis of the parameters derived from these data permitted differentiation of normal, adipose, benign, and malignant breast pathologies. The results provide a strong correlation between tissue microstructure and ultrasonic parameters relative to the morphology and stiffness of microscopic features such as ductules, lobules, and fibrous structures. Ultrasonic testing of bovine heart, liver, and kidney tissues supports this correlation, showing that tissues having stiff fiber-like or filled-duct structures, such as myocardium or ductal carcinomas, display greater peak densities in the ultrasonic spectra than tissues with soft, open duct-like structures, such as kidney tissue or normal breast glands. The sensitivity of high-frequency ultrasound to histopathology may assist in eliminating invasive re-excision for lumpectomy patients. [Work supported by NIH R21CA131798.].</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22979697</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Histological analysis of biological tissues using high-frequency ultrasound.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>In this work, we report the use of ultrasonic acoustophoresis for the label-free separation of viable and non-viable mammalian cells within a microfluidic device. This device exploits the fact that cells that have undergone apoptosis are physically smaller than viable cells, and achieves efficient sorting based on the strong size dependence of acoustic radiation forces in the microchannel. As a model, we have selectively enriched viable MCF-7 breast tumor cells from heterogeneous mixtures of viable and non-viable cells. We found that this mode of separation is gentle on cells, while enabling label-free separation at sample flow-rates of up to 12 mL/hr at a cell density of 10(6) cells/mL. We have extensively characterized the device and report the effects of piezoelectric voltage and sample flow-rate on device performance, and describe how these parameters can be tuned to optimize recovery, purity or throughput.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22979274</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Acoustophoretic cell sorting in microfluidic channels.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Magnetic resonance images with an isotropic resolution of 200 microns were collected for two human breast specimens. The images were interpolated to achieve a resolution of 50 microns and segmented to produce images of skin, fat, muscle, ductal structures, and connective tissues in consultation with a breast pathologist. The images were then mapped to acoustic parameters of sound speed, absorption and density. Calculations of acoustic propagation of fields radiated by point sources outside of the specimens were performed using the k-space finite-difference time-domain method and the frequency-domain fast multipole method. Time-domain k-space results were Fourier transformed and the 3-MHz component was compared to 3-MHz frequency-domain calculations. For the first model, measuring 1180 × 1190 × 290 voxels, the two methods were found to agree in a representative coronal slice to within 5.0% (RMS). The second specimen, comprising 1350 × 1170 × 790 voxels, yielded temporal and frequency-domain results that agreed to within 5.8% (RMS) in a representative coronal slice. Comparable results were obtained in other planes orthogonal to the representative slices. The close agreement establishes confidence in the accuracy of the methods when simulating propagation through large, complicated, realistic models of human tissue.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22979132</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Validation of time-domain and frequency-domain calculations of acoustic propagation from breast models derived from magnetic resonance images.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Ultrasound tomography (UST) is being developed to address the limitations of mammography in breast cancer detection. Central to the success of UST is the possibility of obtaining high-resolution images of tissue mechanical properties across the whole breast. A recent paper [Huthwaite and Simonetti, J. Acoust. Soc. Am. 130, 1721-1734 (2011)] made use of a numerical phantom to demonstrate that sufficient image resolution can be obtained by simply treating refraction and diffraction effects in consecutive steps through the combination of ray-based time of flight and diffraction tomography. This letter presents the first experimental demonstration of the method using phantom and invivo data from a cancer patient.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22978851</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Combining time of flight and diffraction tomography for high resolution breast imaging: Initial invivo results (L).</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>1. A study was designed to characterise dark, firm, dry (DFD) breast meat resulting from cold exposure of broilers and compare its properties with normal breast meat from cold-stressed and control birds. 2. A total of 140 broilers were selected from 5- and 6-week-old birds exposed to cold temperatures ranging from -18 to -4°C, or a control temperature of +20°C for 3 h in an environmental chamber. Half of these birds were slaughtered immediately following the cold exposure and the other half were given 2 h of lairage. 3. Breast meat samples were categorised based on ultimate pH (pH(u)) and colour L* (lightness) values into normal (5·7 ≤ pH(u) ≤ 6·1; 46 ≤ L* ≤ 53) breast meat from control (control-normal) or cold-stressed (cold-normal) birds, and DFD (pH(u) > 6·1; L* < 46) breast meat, which only occurred in cold-stressed birds (cold-DFD). 4. Residual glycogen was not different between cold-DFD and control-normal breast meat. Lactate concentration was lower in cold-DFD compared with control-normal breast meat. Lactate concentration almost tripled for all the samples by 30 h post-mortem, which resulted in a drop in pH of normal meat, but did not have any effect on pH of DFD breast meat. Glycolytic potential at both 5 min and 30 h post-mortem was lower in DFD breast meat compared with the normal breast meat from both cold-stressed and control birds. 5. Cold-DFD breast meat was significantly darker, with higher pH(u), lower cook loss, higher water-binding capacity and processing cook yield than cold-normal and control-normal breast meat, which were not different from each other.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22978591</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Characteristics of cold-induced dark, firm, dry broiler chicken breast meat.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Purpose The anticancer drug 5-fluorouracile (5-FU) which is indicated for the treatment of a variety of solid malignancies such as colorectal, breast, head and neck neoplasms is extensively biotransformed to 5- fluoro-5,6-dihydrouracil (5-FDHU) by the dihydropyrimidine deshydrogenase enzyme (DPD). DPD deficiency is recognized as an important risk factor, predisposing patient to undergo severe/lethal toxicities. To date, relationships between 5-FU, 5-FDHU and toxicity following iv bolus administration has not been studied using the population pharmacokinetics approach. Methods Retrospective pharmacokinetic data of 5-FU and 5-FDHU from 127 colorectal cancer patients were used for the population pharmacokinetic analysis. Treatment schedule consisted of an adjuvant therapy with 5-FU plus leucovorin. 5-FU and 5-FDHU complete plasma profiles recorded on day-1 of the first chemotherapy cycle were modeled simultaneously using NONMEM software. Gastro-intestinal adverse events graded according to the WHO criteria were recorded after the first cycle. A population logistic regression model was developed to identify predictive factors of these adverse events. Results A three-compartment pharmacokinetic mixture model best described 5-FU and 5-FDHU kinetics profiles. Linear and saturated elimination from the central compartment of 5-FU and a linear elimination from the 5-FDHU compartment were used. A bimodal distribution of the intercompartmental clearance was observed allowing two subpopulation with high (17 L/h) and low values (3.35 L/h). DPD-phenotype is suspected to explain this mixture. No covariates were introduced in the final model. Also, no relationship was found between maximal metabolism rate and DPD-phenotype. Predictive factors associated with occurrence of high grade gastro-intestinal adverse events were gender, dose and lean body mass suggesting serious cautions with the BSA- weighted dose for women. For the low-grade toxicities, 5-FU area under curve was predictive for woman and 5-FDHU area under curve for men. 3 Conclusion A population pharmacokinetic mixture model was developed to describe kinetic profiles of 5-FU and its major metabolite. This model has significant implications, to identify patients with potentially low DPD phenotype requiring earlier adjustment of the 5-FU dose. Also this analysis highlights the need for developing alternative dosing-scheme for women.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22978343</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Population Pharmacokinetic Analysis of 5-FU and 5-FDHU in Colorectal Cancer Patients: search for biomarkers associated with gastro-intestinal toxicity.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Combining several cytotoxics is the current mainstay for treating breast cancer patients. The combination between capecitabine and docetaxel was found to be more efficient than capecitabine or docetaxel when both were used as single agents. However, the administration protocol for this combination has been empirically chosen from single-agent trials. Based on already available population analysis, we propose here to optimize the administration protocol of this association so as to enhance efficacy while limiting treatment-related toxicity. Efficacy parameters evaluated from population analysis using a disturbed tumor growth model and safety characteristics from the available databases evidenced that: 1) Docetaxel is more efficient than capecitabine at the start of the treatment, but becomes less efficient next because of acquisition of resistance; 2) Over a long period of time, capecitabine is better tolerated than docetaxel. These characteristics allowed the following recommendations for an optimized modality of combination: 1) The treatment has to be started at the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) for docetaxel; this dose should be individualized right from the start of the second cycle of treatment; 2) In parallel, capecitabine has to be started at a dose lower than its MTD. 3) When docetaxel becomes less efficient than capecitabine because of resistance, docetaxel dose has to be reduced but not discontinued. 4) If adverse events show during the treatment, it is recommended to reduce docetaxel, rather than capecitabine dosage. Combining modeling and statistical analysis of clinical data permit to optimize combination treatments. This procedure could be extended to others treatments involving combination of several cytotoxics.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22978334</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Optimized administration protocol of capecitabine plus docetaxel combination in metastatic breast cancer patients.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Betulin, an important compound found in birch tree bark, can be converted to betulinic acid, an important pharmacological substance. Betulin has recently been reported as a cytotoxic agent for several tumor cell lines and as an apoptotic inductor. Angiogenesis is a key process involved in tumor metastasis and in developing tumor resistance to cytotoxic therapy. There are little data on betulin as an anti angiogenic agent. This preliminary study aimed to evaluate the cytotoxic effect of betulin on three cancer cell lines: HeLa (cervix adenocarcinoma), MCF7 (breast adenocarcinoma) and A431 (skin epidermoid carcinoma), and the apoptotic mechanism, as well as the implication in the capillary formation of the chicken embryo chorioallantoic membrane. The analysis consisted in the interpretation of the MTT assay and fluorescence double staining with Hoechst dye 33258 and propidium iodide, while the angiogenic effect was evaluated using morphological and immunohistochemical techniques. The antitumor activity is revealed by the double fluorescence staining, indicating that at higher concentrations, the cell membrane permeability is enhanced, while at lower concentrations there is evidence for nuclear fragmentation. In what concerns its effect on the process of blood vessel formation, betulin induced the reduction of newly formed capillaries, especially in the mesenchyme, possible through targeting the normal function of endothelial cells. In vitro results proved the superior specificity of betulin on cervical cancer cells, followed by skin cancer cells.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22978210</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Betulin as an antitumor agent tested in vitro on A431, hela and MCF7, and as an angiogenic inhibitor in vivo in the CAM assay.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Inula aucheriana n-hexane, CHCl3 and MeOH extracts were evaluated for their anti-proliferative activity against HepG-2, MCF-7, MDBK and A-549 cells. The CHCl3 extract exhibited cytotoxic activity to the above cell lines with IC50 values of 13.5, 23.4, 10.5, and 26.9 microg/mL, respectively. The sesquiterpene lactone britannin was isolated from the above extract. This was further evaluated in the MTT assay to demonstrate strong cytotoxicity to the mentioned cell lines (IC50: 2.2, 5.9, 5.4, and 3.5 microg/mL, respectively), and the apoptotic inducing properties of britannin were evaluated on human breast adenocarcinoma (MCF-7) cells through the terminal deoxynucleotidyl transferase dUTP nick end labeling (TUNEL) assay.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22978209</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Anti-proliferative activity and apoptotic potential of britannin, a sesquiterpene lactone from Inula aucheriana.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>To study the effects of arsenic trioxide (As2O3) on the proliferation and the migration force of human breast cancer SKBR-3 cell and the expression of Notch1.SKBR-3 cells were cultured with different concentrations of As2O3 for 24 h and with the final concentration of 8 micromol/L for 24, 48, and 72 h. The effects of As2O3 on the cell proliferation of SKBR-3 were detected by MTT assay. The effects of the migration force of SKBR-3 cells were detected by Transwell. The expression of Notch1 mRNA was detected using reverse transcription polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR). The expression of Notch1 protein was detected using Western blot.As2O3 could significantly inhibit the proliferation of SKBR-3 cells in a concentration- and time-dependent manner (P < 0.05). It also could inhibit the migration force of SKBR-3 cells (P < 0.05). Results of RT-PCR and Western blot showed that Notch1 mRNA and protein levels obviously decreased (P < 0.05).As2O3 could inhibit the expression of Notch1 and the cell proliferation and the migration force of SKBR-3 cells, which primarily revealed that As2O3 might affect the biological behavior of human breast cancer cells possibly through Notch1 signaling pathway, thus providing theoretical and experimental bases for treating breast cancer by arsenics.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22978106</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>[Effects of arsenic trioxide on the proliferation of human breast cancer SKBR-3 cell and the expression of Notch1].</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Breast cancer is the most common visceral neoplasm which metastatizes in skin. Skin infiltration by breast cancer may appear as various types of neoplastic/inflammatory lesions, including plaques, pigskin-like areas, scirrhous morphea-like lesions, nodules, zosteriform lesions, and papulovescicles. An unusual form of cutaneous infiltration involving a mammary region bearing a post-mastectomy surgical skin scar is herein described: interestingly, such a cutaneous cancer involvement could not be included in the above classification, because it merely consisted of red-purple areas dealing with small telangiectasias, without any sign of inflammation.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22978058</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Unusual form of cutaneous infiltration by cancer.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>We investigated the effects of resveratrol on metastasis in in vitro and in vivo systems. 4T1 cells were cultured in the presence of various concentrations (0-30 µmol/L) of resveratrol. For experimental metastasis, BALB/c mice were injected intravenously with 4T1 cells in the tail vein, and were orally administered various concentrations (0, 100, or 200 mg/kg Body weight) of resveratrol for 21 days. After resveratrol treatment, cell adhesion, wound migration, invasion, and MMP-9 activity were significantly decreased in a dose-dependent manner in 4T1 cells (P < 0.05). The numbers of pulmonary nodules were significantly decreased in mice fed the resveratrol (P < 0.05). The plasma MMP-9 activity was decreased in response to treatment with resveratrol in mice (P < 0.05). We conclude that resveratrol inhibits cancer metastasis both in vitro and in vivo, and this inhibition is likely due to the decrease in MMP-9 activity caused by resveratrol.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22977682</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Effect of resveratrol on the metastasis of 4T1 mouse breast cancer cells in vitro and in vivo.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Introduction: Many case reports have described anatomical variants of the pectoralis muscles. However, there is a paucity of published literature on the consequence of such presentations in reconstructive breast surgery. Methods: A 45-year-old female patient with breast cancer presented for left mastectomy and immediate reconstruction with tissue expander. During mastectomy, she was noted to have an extra muscle anterior to her pectoralis major muscle. This variant had not previously been described in the literature and was therefore named the oblique pectoralis anterior. After inspection of the aberrant musculature, the decision was made to release the inferolateral insertion of the accessory muscle with the inferior edge of pectoralis major. An adequate pocket for the expander was created. Results: After routine expansion and implant exchange, muscular coverage of the implant from pectoralis major and the oblique pectoralis anterior muscle approximated 70%. The patient was left with good symmetry and a cosmetic result, despite the challenges presented by her anomalous chest wall musculature. Discussion: Prior knowledge of the various anatomic aberrations described in the literature can prepare a surgeon to properly incorporate and utilize the variant anatomy, should it be encountered, to benefit the outcome of the operation.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22977679</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Implications of anomalous pectoralis muscle in reconstructive breast surgery: the oblique pectoralis anterior.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Objectives: To propose initiatives and actions that could improve access to and outcomes from oncoplastic breast surgery. Methods: The author group met in May 2010 to draft position statements on key unmet needs in oncoplastic breast surgery and how these may be addressed. At a second meeting in December 2010, the statements were voted upon and adjusted as necessary to achieve unanimous agreement. Results: It was agreed that every patient undergoing breast cancer surgery should be assessed by an oncoplastic team capable of offering the full range of surgical options. However, currently, not all women are adequately informed about the surgical options available. Furthermore, levels of multidisciplinary working, standards of care, and levels of surgical training in the full range of breast oncoplastic techniques are suboptimal. Institution-specific guidelines relating to the optimal patient pathway, the definition of clinical standards, and improved education in reconstructive surgery are required. Oncoplastic breast surgery should be offered to all patients, within the context of multidisciplinary teams that include accredited surgeons who consult with each other early in the treatment pathway. These teams should be focused on achieving not just positive oncologic outcomes, but also esthetic outcomes in line with patient wishes, to achieve optimal quality of life. Conclusions: There is a desire within the surgical community to improve patient outcomes by better incorporating oncoplastic procedures into the treatment pathways for breast cancer. These position statements represent the perspectives of a group of European plastic surgeons on the key elements required to achieve this goal.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22977675</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>A position statement on optimizing the role of oncoplastic breast surgery.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string></string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22977672</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>LETTER TO THE EDITOR A New Application to Free-Nipple-Graft Reduction Mammaplasty for Breast and Nipple Projection.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Knowledge concerning concordance of epidermal growth factor receptor 2 (HER2) expression between primary breast cancers and asynchronous local-regional recurrences is sparse. Receptor characteristics could be altered with time and may be affected by anticancer treatment. It remains uncertain whether recurrences have the identical or similar HER2 receptor expression pattern as the primary breast cancer. The aim of the present study was to evaluate whether HER2 is stable during the process of recurrence. Expression of HER2 was investigated immunohistochemically in paired samples of primary breast cancers and corresponding asynchronous local-regional recurrences (n=35). HER2 expression was scored as 0, 1+, 2+ or 3+. HER2 overexpression (2+ or 3+) was found in 48.57% (17/35) of the primary breast cancers and 45.71% (16/35) of the corresponding local-regional recurrences. A concordance of HER2 overexpression between the primary lesions and matching regional recurrences was observed in 85.71% of the breast cancer cases. Five out of the 35 paired samples (14.28%) were discordant. Only 3 patients who had 2+ HER2 expression in the primary tumors showed HER2 down-regulation (0 or 1+) in the recurrences, while the HER2 score in 2 patients changed oppositely. Moreover, all of the cases with 3+ HER2 staining in the primary lesions retained HER2 overexpression in the recurrences. The HER2 is commonly expressed in breast cancer, and its expression in the primary tumors and the corresponding recurrences was concordant in the majority of the cases. As the receptor expression may lose or gain in recurrences at a probability of approximately 10%, assessment of the receptor status in recurrences is still encouraged.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22977642</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Human epidermal growth factor receptor 2 protein expression between primary breast cancer and paired asynchronous local-regional recurrences.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>We previously reported BRCA1 mutations and sequence variants in Sri Lankan breast cancer patients. Mutations and sequence variants of the BRCA2 gene were studied in 149 study participants from the same cohort. There were 55 familial and 54 sporadic breast cancer patients, 20 at-risk individuals and 20 healthy controls. Direct sequencing (exon 11) and sequencing of abnormal bands after screening with single-strand conformation polymorphism (remaining exons) were used to detect mutations and sequence variants. Twenty-three sequence variants were found in the BRCA2 gene. Two novel pathogenic frame-shift additions resulting in a premature stop codon (c.2403 insA/exon 11, c.2667 insT/exon 11) were identified. Possibly pathogenic two novel missense mutations (c.1191 A>C/exon 10, c.5695 A>C/exon 11) one novel intronic variant (IVS15-21 insTT), four novel silent mutations (c.969 C>T/exon 9, c.1353 C>T/exon 10, c.2766 A>C/exon 11 and c.7452 A>G/exon 14) and one novel missense mutation (c.971 C>G/exon 9) were observed. One previously reported possibly pathogenic intronic variant (IVS81 G>C) and several previously reported silent mutations, missense mutations, and one 5' UTR polymorphism were detected. Pathogenic and possibly pathogenic mutations were more frequent in the BRCA2 gene among Sri Lankan familial breast cancer patients when compared to our previous findings for the BRCA1 gene.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22977638</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Novel sequence variants and common recurrent polymorphisms of BRCA2 in Sri Lankan breast cancer patients and a family with BRCA1 mutations.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Overexpression of breast cancer resistance protein, the ATP-binding cassette, subfamily G, member2 (BCRP/ABCG2), confers multidrug resistance to tumor cells and often limits the efficacy of chemotherapy. The aim of this study was to investigate the expression and functional activity of ABCG2 in head and neck squamous cell carcinoma (HNSCC) and corresponding cell lines. Immunohistochemistry was performed to investigate the presence of the ABCG2 transporter in HNSCC tissues. Expression of ABCG2 in the Hep-2, Hep-2T, CNE and FaDu cell lines was analyzed by real-time quantitative reverse transcription-polymerase chain reaction and Western blotting at the levels of messenger RNA (mRNA) and protein, respectively. The drug sensitivity of the above four cell lines to mitoxantrone was detected using MTT, and the drug accumulation of mitoxantrone was analyzed by flow cytometry. Positive expression of ABCG2 was detected in 52.04% of the laryngeal cancer samples from 98 patients, in 65% of the 40 hypopharyngeal cancer samples and in 58.82% of the 34 nasopharyngeal cancer samples. The level of expression was found to be correlated with tumor TNM stage (P<0.05) and lymph node metastasis (P<0.01). All four HNSCC cell lines expressed ABCG2 at the mRNA and protein levels. The levels of ABCG2 expression in the four cell lines were significantly correlated with the function and sensitivity to mitoxantrone. The addition of fumitremorgin C at a concentration of 5 μM to mitoxantrone treatment caused a varied increase in mitoxantrone accumulation of 1.09-fold, 1.33-fold (P<0.01), 1.4-fold (P<0.01) and 1-fold in the Hep-2, Hep-2T, CNE and FaDu cells, respectively. Expression of ABCG2 varied among the different types of carcinoma tissues and each HNSCC cell line, and it induced multidrug resistance and separation of cancer stem cells attributing to its efflux pump function. Thus, ABCG2 expression may be an unfavorable prognostic factor for HNSCC. Due to the negligible expression and function of ABCG2, we suggest that the FaDu cell line is suitable to be a negative control in studies involving HNSCC. Taken together, ABCG2 is a promising universal biomarker of cancer stem cells and a target gene for HNSCC chemotherapy.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22977636</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Expression and function of ABCG2 in head and neck squamous cell carcinoma and cell lines.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>DBC1/KIAA1967 (deleted in breast cancer 1) is a putative tumor-suppressor gene cloned from breast cancer specimens and is reported to regulate p53-dependent apoptosis through its specific inhibition of SIRT1 deacetylase. Although SIRT1 plays a pivotal role in carcinogenesis by regulating cellular proliferation, survival and death, its role in breast cancer remains controversial. Therefore, we aimed to investigate the expression status and clinicopathological significance of DBC1 and SIRT1 in breast cancer tissues. We evaluated the expression of DBC1 and SIRT1 in breast core-needle biopsy specimens from 48 primary breast cancer patients between 2005 and 2008. These patients were treated with primary systemic chemotherapy and subsequent surgical resection of the lesions. Immunohistochemical expression scores of DBC1 and SIRT1 were evaluated, and the relationship between their expression levels and clinicopathological features of breast cancer was analyzed. The expression was observed exclusively in the nuclei of normal and neoplastic ductal cells. In breast biopsy specimens, positive expression of DBC1 and SIRT1 was noted in 85 and 98% of patients, respectively. Expression of DBC1 was significantly associated with the tumor nuclear grade (P=0.019). DBC1 and SIRT1 expression was inversely correlated with HER2 expression (P=0.026 and 0.003, respectively). Lower expression of DBC1 and SIRT1 indicated a tendency for a favorable pathological response to chemotherapy, although this was not statistically significant. Our results reveal that the expression of DBC1 and SIRT1 in breast tissues is associated with tumor characteristics.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22977628</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Expression of DBC1 is associated with nuclear grade and HER2 expression in breast cancer.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Papillary lesions of the breast include a broad spectrum of lesions, from benign papillomas to papillary carcinomas. It is difficult to determine whether a lesion is benign or malignant based on the fragmented material of a core needle biopsy (CNB). This study evaluated patients with papillary lesions examined using CNB. We retrospectively reviewed 31 papillary lesions diagnosed using CNB between 2004 and 2007. The clinical findings of benign and malignant papillary lesions were compared. The average patient age was 48.9 years. Twelve patients presented with a discharge and 10 patients presented with a lump. Eight patients were asymptomatic. The initial diagnoses by CNB of the 31 lesions were 25 intraductal papillomas, 4 intracystic papillomas and 2 adenomas. After CNB, excisional biopsies were performed in 23 patients and biopsies with a Mammotome(®) in 2 patients. Seven patients underwent regular follow-up. Five (16%) of the 31 patients with papillary lesions were ultimately diagnosed with breast cancer. The average distance from the nipple to a tumor diagnosed as malignant was 2.46 cm, which was longer than for a tumor diagnosed as benign. Ultimately, 5 papillary lesions (16%) were diagnosed as breast cancer. To avoid overlooking a malignancy, surgical excision is advantageous for papillary lesions, particularly those located far from the nipple.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22977622</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Papillary lesions of the breast diagnosed using core needle biopsies.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
  <void method="add">
   <object class="biowizard.dict.DictionaryEntryArticle">
    <void property="abstractText">
     <string>Various published studies have been inconclusive in attempting to relate a family history of breast and/or ovarian cancer (BOC) to the survival of breast cancer patients. The aim of the study was to investigate the association of a family history of BOC with tumor characteristics, treatment response and the difference between the prognosis of familial breast cancer (FBC) patients and sporadic breast cancer (SBC) patients. Data on 348 operable FBC patients and 345 SBC patients were retrospectively analyzed. The overall survival (OS) and recurrence/metastasis-free survival (RFS) were compared for both groups. FBC cases were diagnosed at a relatively younger age (51.1±10.4 vs. 53.7±11.0 years, P=0.054) and presented a lower T stage (P=0.000) than the SBC cases. Patients with a family history of BOC had a significantly greater risk of recurrence/metastasis (P= 0.04) and a non-significantly increased risk of death (P=0.06) compared to the SBC patients. In a multivariate analysis, family history of BOC was an independent predictive factor for both recurrence/metastasis rate (P=0.01, HR=0.012, 95% CI 0.02-0.57) and mortality (P=0.044, HR=0.43, 95% CI 0.19-0.98) in the hormone receptor-positive population. Our results found that women diagnosed with FBC had an early onset of disease in the population studied, and the poor outcome of patients with a family history of BOC associated with survival was restricted to the hormone receptor-positive population.</string>
    </void>
    <void property="id">
     <string>22977598</string>
    </void>
    <void property="title">
     <string>Influence of a family history of breast and/or ovarian cancer on breast cancer outcomes.</string>
	</void>
   </object>
  </void>
 </object>
</java>